翻译：SWAT1909  时间轴：explosiveskull  校对：w2jmoe
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-
好吧  我们最后再来一次
All right, let's do this one last time.
我叫彼得·帕克
My name is Peter Parker.
我被一只受过辐射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
十年来
And for 10 years...
十年来我是唯一的蜘蛛侠
I've been the one and only Spider-Man.
剩下的你们肯定都知道了
I'm pretty sure you know the rest.
能力越大  责任越大
With great power comes great responsibility.
我救过一群人  坠入过爱河  拯救过这座城市
I saved a bunch of people, fell in love, saved the city.
然后我一而再再而三地拯救
And then I saved the city again and again and again and again.
还有  呃
And I did, uh...
我做这个
I did this.
♪ Get on up Get yourself together ♪
♪ Drive that funky soul ♪
我们不必认真地谈论这个事
We don't really talk about this.
看  我是本漫画书  是份麦片
Look, I'm a comic book. I'm a cereal.
我做了一张圣诞专辑
Did a Christmas album.
我有一首很棒的主题曲
I have an excellent theme song.
♪ Spider-man Spider-man ♪
还有不怎么样的冰棒
And a so-so popsicle.
我是说  我看起来更糟了
I mean, I've looked worse.
但经历过这一切后
But after everything...
我还是喜欢当蜘蛛侠
I still love being Spider-Man.
我是说谁不喜欢呢?
I mean, who wouldn't?
所以无论我被揍了多少次
So no matter how many hits I take...
我总能找到办法回来
...I always find a way to come back.
因为在这座城市和被遗忘之间唯一的东西
Because the only thing standing between this city and oblivion
就是我
is me.
唯一一个蜘蛛侠
There's only one Spider-Man.
你正在看着他
And you're lookin' at him.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Needless to say... ♪
♪ Nevertheless Callin' it quits ♪
- ♪ Now, baby, I'm a wreck ♪
迈尔斯  爸爸  该去学校了
Miles, papá, time for school!
迈尔斯
Miles!
迈尔斯  是
- Miles! - Yeah!?
你收拾好上学的行李了吗?
Are you finished packing for school?
是吧
Yeah.
我只是在熨最后一件衬衫
Just ironing my last shirt.
快点  伙计
Vamo chacho!
♪ You're a sunflower... ♪
快点  你现在是大人了
Come on! You a grown man now.
让我们展示给老师们看看  -迈尔斯
- Let's show these teachers that. - Miles!
我的笔记本电脑哪去了?
Where's my laptop?
如果你想让我开车送你  我们现在就要动身了
If you want me to drive you, we gotta go now.
不  爸爸  我走路
No, Dad, I'll walk.
私人司机去过一次  -没关系
- Personal chauffeur going once. - It's okay.
玛丽亚  这孩子疯了
Ay Maria, este nene me tiene loca!
迈尔斯  得走了  -等一下
- Miles! Gotta go. - In a minute!
-得走了  -等等
- Gotta go. - In a minute!
妈妈  我得走了
Mom, I gotta go.
等一下嘛
In a minute.
爸爸  打电话给我
Papá! Llamame!
周五见哦
See you Friday.
好的  妈妈  再见
Okay, mami. Hasta luego!
看看谁回来了  怎么了兄弟?
Look who's back. Yo, what's going on, bro?
嘿  我只是路过  你好吗?
Hey, I'm just walking by. How you doin'?
迈尔斯  你在学校好吗?
Miles! Te va bien en la escuela?
我敢肯定很好
Seguro que si
哟  迈尔斯  你昨晚感觉到地震了吗?
Yo, Miles! You feel that earthquake last night?
你在说什么呢?  我昨晚睡得很香
What you talkin' about? I slept like a baby last night.
新学校怎么样?  很轻松
- How's that new school? - So easy.
我们想念你  迈尔斯  -你想我吗? 我还住在这啊
- We miss you, Miles. - You miss me? I still live here!
等等  你想我?
Wait, you miss me?
噢  拜托
Oh, come on.
讲真  爸爸  走路就行了
Seriously, Dad. Walking would've been fine.
星期六你可以多走几步
You can walk plenty on Saturday
前提是你要把那些贴纸撕掉
when you peel those stickers off.
你看到了? 我不清楚那是不是我
You saw that? I don't know if that was me.
还有昨天在克林顿贴的两个
And the two from yesterday on Clinton.
嗯  那些是我干的
Yeah, those were me.
所以  看看那  另一家新开的咖啡店
Soooo... look at that. Another new coffee shop.
你看到了吗?  迈尔斯  -当然
- You see that Miles? - Totally. Yeah.
你看到那个了吗  那个叫啥?  -泡沫派对
You see that one, what's that one called? - Foam Party.
“泡沫派对”  别吧
"Foam Party"? Come on.
大家都在排队  你看那  迈尔斯
And everyone is just linin' up. You see that, Miles
我看到了
I see it.
那是咖啡店还是迪厅啊?
Is that a coffee shop or a disco?
爸  你过时了
Dad, you're old, man.
昨晚有很多
There are multiple reports
关于神秘地震事件的报道
of another mysterious seismic event last night.
接近蜘蛛侠的消息人士称  他正在调查这个问题
Sources close to SpiderMan say he's looking into the problem.
蜘蛛侠  我是说  这家伙每天
Spider-Man. I mean, this guy swings in once a day,
都会戴着他的小面具来一趟  然后不和任何人说话  对吧?
zip-zap-zop in his little mask and answers to no one. Right?
是啊  爸爸
Yeah, Dad.
与此同时  我的人还在外面
And meanwhile my guys are out there,
冒着生命危险  不戴面具
- lives on the line, no masks. - Uh-huh.
露脸  肩负责任
- We show our faces. Accountability.
哦  不  爸爸  开快点  我认识这些孩子
Oh no! Dad, speed up, I know these kids
你懂的  能力越大  责任就越大
You know, with great ability comes great accountability
俗话可不是这么说的  爸爸
That's not even how the saying goes, Dad
我真的很喜欢蜘蛛侠的麦片粥  我会给他的
I do like his cereal though, I'll give him that
哦  天啊  警察不闯红灯吗?
Oh my gosh. Don't cops run red lights?
有人会  但不是你爸爸
Some do... but not your Dad!
♪ My memories keep begging ♪
♪ For someone else ♪
♪ I know this feeling, yes I know it very well ♪
布鲁克林愿景学校
为什么我不能回到布鲁克林中学?
Why can't I go back to Brooklyn Middle?
迈尔斯  你已经坚持两个星期了
Miles, you've given it two weeks.
我们不会再谈这个事了
We're not having this conversation.
我认为这所新学校是精英学校
I just think that this new school is elitist.
“精英学校”?  -我更喜欢
- "Elitist"? - And I would prefer to be
在人多的普通学校
at a normal school among the people.
“人”?  这些都是人
"The people"? These are your people.
我来这里是因为我中了愚蠢的彩票
I'm only here 'cause I won that stupid lottery.
没办法  你和其他人一样通过了入学考试  好吗
No way. You passed the entry test just like everybody else, ok!
你现在有机会了 你想搞砸吗?
You have an opportunity here. You wanna blow that?
你想像你叔叔一样结束吗?
You wanna end up like your uncle?
艾伦叔叔怎么了?  他是个好人
What's wrong with Uncle Aaron? He's a good guy.
我们都会在生活中做出选择
We all make choices in life.
我觉得现在别无选择
It doesn't feel like I have a choice right now.
你没得选
You Don't！
我爱你  迈尔斯
I love you, Miles.
是的  我知道  爸爸  周五见
Yeah, I know, Dad. See you Friday
你也应该对我说  我爱你
You gotta say I love you back.
爸爸  你是认真的?
Dad are you serious?
我要听你说
I wanna hear it.
你真要听我说?
You wanna hear me say it?
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
这可是学校门口
You're dropping me off at a school.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you Dad
看看这周围
Look at this place.
爸爸  我爱你
Dad, I love you.
收到
That's a copy.
把鞋带系好
Tie your shoes, please.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad!
嘿  早上好  你在做什么?
Hey, good morning. How you doin'?
周末很短  嗯哼?  -收到
- Weekend was short, huh? - "That's a copy."
天啊  这太尴尬了
Oh, my gosh! This is embarrassing.
我们撞衫了
We wore the same jacket.
嘿
Hey.
怎么?
Yeah?
你的鞋带松了
Your shoe's untied.
是啊  我知道  这是个选择
Yeah, I'm aware. It's a choice.
♪ Theory is that All matter is composed ♪
♪ Of at least three ♪
♪ Fundamental particles ♪
谁能解出这题的XY?
Who can solve this for XY?
这就叫做三段论法
And that is known as a syllogism.
回去读完《远大前程》的两个章节
Tonight, read two chapters of Great Expectations
随堂测验容积和压力
A take-home quiz on volumetric pressure.
五页纸的论文  结论是重点
A five page essay with your conclusions stressed.
工人党
Workers Party
家庭作业
Take-home Work
会有无数种可能
...countless other possibilities.
在另一个宇宙我可能穿的是红衣服
There could be a universe where I am wearing red.
又或者是皮裤
Or wearing leather pants.
偷偷溜进来的莫拉莱斯先生  你又迟到了
Mr. Morales, moving in the dark. You're late again.
爱因斯坦说过时间是相对的  不是吗?
Einstein said time was relative, right?
或许我没有迟到  只是你们早到了
Maybe I'm not late. Maybe you guys are early.
抱歉  我只是觉得太安静了
Sorry. It was just so quiet.
你是想继续站着还是坐下呢?
Would you like to keep standing there or do you want to sit down?
我们所处的宇宙  其实是多个平行宇宙中的一个
Our universe is, in fact, one of many parallel universes
这些平行宇宙是同时存在的
happening at the exact same time.
多亏了菲斯克家族科研基金会的所有人
Thanks to everyone here at the Fisk Family Foundation for the Sciences...
我喜欢你的笑话  -真的吗?
- I liked your joke. - Really?
我的意思是这并不好笑  所以我才会笑
I mean, it wasn't funny. That's why I laughed.
不过想法不错  所以我喜欢
But it was smart, so I liked it.
我好像之前没见过你
I don't think I've seen you before.
嘘
Shhhhh!
我们所做的每一个选择
Every choice that we make
都会创造出各种可能性
would create countless other possibilities.
而这些可能性是无穷的
A what-if to infinity.
零鸭蛋?  再多拿几个零分
A zero? A few more of those,
你应该就会把我开除了吧?
you'd probably have to kick me outta here, huh?
或许我不适合这个学校
Maybe I'm just not right for this school.
如果一个人闭着眼睛
If a person wearing a blind fold
在一堆判断题里随便乱选
picked the answers on a true or false quiz at random,
你猜准确率是多少?
do you know what score they would get?
百分之五十?
Fifty percent?
回答正确
That's right!
等等
Wait wait!
能正确避开所有正确答案
The only way to get all the answers wrong
那就证明你其实全都会
is to know which answers are right.
你故意想被开除
You're trying to quit.
我是不会答应的
And I'm not gonna let you.
我要罚你写篇关于自己的文章
I'm assigning you a personal essay.
不是关于物理  而是关于你自己的
Not about physics, but about you,
你想成为什么样的人
and what kind of person you want to be.
远大前程
- ♪ Unh. Unh ♪ - ♪ Unh. Unh ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Ha, sicker than Your average ♪
♪ Poppa twist cabbage Off instinct ♪
♪ Don't think ♪
♪ My Detroit players, timbs for My hooligans in Brooklyn ♪
♪ Dead right, if the head Right, Biggie there e'rynight ♪
♪ Never lose, never choose to Bruise crews who ♪
- ♪ Do something to us... ♪ - ♪ Come on ♪
艾伦叔叔  嘿  吓一跳吧
Uncle Aaroooooon! Hey! Were you scared?!
想领教一下吗?
You want that, huh?
学校怎么样?
What's up with school?
好得不行  朋友多到乐翻天
Going great. Got tons of friends.
总不见得一无是处吧
You can't tell me it's all that bad there.
聪明的姑娘总是那么迷人
Smart girls is where it's at.
那里应该有很多才是
Place must be full of 'em.
不  没这回事  根本没有
No, there's no one. There's no one.
做我的侄子可不能那么没戏
Yo I cannot have a nephew of mine on the streets with no game.
谁说我没戏了
I got game!
有个新来的姑娘
There was a new girl,
她还挺喜欢我的  你懂的
Actually, you know, she's kinda into me. You know how it is.
她叫什么?
What's her name?
你懂的  我们还在建立感情阶段
You know we... this is... we're laying down the ground work right now.
你知道搭肩膀这招吗?
You know about the shoulder touch?
当然知道  不过  说来听听
Of course I do! But tell me anyway.
明天去找那姑娘  走到她前面  然后
Tomorrow find that girl, walk up to her and be like...
嘿
Hey
逗我吗?  艾伦叔叔
You serious Uncle Aaron?
我告诉你  这招很有技术含量
I'm telling you man, it's science.
走到她面前  然后说  嘿
So walk up to her and be like... hey.
不  不  不  应该是  像这样  嘿
No no no no... like hey...
嘿
Hey
不  嘿
No. “Heyyy”
嘿
Heyyyyy.
你真是我亲侄子吗?
You sure you're my nephew, man?
爸爸
作业做完了吗?
你真是我亲侄子吗?
You sure you're my nephew, man?
是她吗?
Is that her?
爸爸
作业做完了吗?
是她吗?
Is that her?
我该走了  还有一篇论文要写
I should probably go. Still got a paper to do tonight.
居然不给我看你的新作  画墙上了吗?
Yo, you've been holding out on me. You throw these up yet?
不  别提了  你也知道我老爸  没戏
No, man, you know my dad. I can't.
来吧  我带你去个好地方
C'mon. I got a spot you ain't gonna believe.
不  不行  不行
I can't! I can't I can't
我会有麻烦的
I'm gonna get in so much trouble.
别怕  告诉你爸是美术老师让的
Hey man, tell them your art teacher made you.
嘿  你怎么会知道这个地方?
Hey, how did you know about this place?
我在这里做过工程
Did an engineering job down here.
♪ One, two, three Four, five... ♪
怎么了?
Wassup?
好吧  看来你是我亲侄子
Yeah man I knew we were related.
哇
Whoa...
布鲁克林
Brooklyn!
这些墙上有很多历史
There's a lot of history on these walls.
这地方太酷了
This is so fresh.
现在看你的了  迈尔斯
Now you're on your own, Miles.
悠着点  很好  很完美
Whoa, slow down a little... that's better... that's perfect.
♪ Who's the black sheep? What's the black sheep? ♪
♪ Don't know who I am When I'm coming so you sleep ♪
看到了吗?  犯错是其中一部分
See what you got now? Makin' mistakes is part of it.
♪ And you can't beat that... ♪
这才是真正的迈尔斯
The real Miles comin' outta hidin'.
♪ You gotta hay?
It's for the hoes ♪
你还可以用其他颜色来勾线
Now you can cut that line with another color.
♪ You can get with this Or you can get with that ♪
♪ You can get with this or You can get with that ♪
♪ I think you'll get with this For this is where it's at ♪
帮个忙?
Little help?
♪ ...who was quite contrary Talkin' 'bout Mary... ♪
想要滴墨效果吗? 这样也挺酷
You want drips? 'Cause if you do, that's cool,
但如果不是  你就得不停地移动
but if you don't, you gotta keep it moving.
要的就是这种效果
That's intentional!
哇  是不是太疯了?
Wow. - Is it too crazy?
不  伙计
No, man.
迈尔斯  我知道你想表达什么
Miles, I see exactly what you're doing there.
没错  我和你爸以前也经常这么干
Yeah. You know me and your Dad used to do this back in the day.
别骗人了
Stop lying.
是真的  有天他当了警察  怎么说呢
It's true. Then he took on the cop thing... and I don't know.
他是个好人  只是
He's a good guy, just...
你懂我的意思
You know what I'm sayin'.
好了  走吧  伙计  我还有事
All right, come on man. I gotta roll.
迈尔斯  快走
Miles, let's go!
真是诡异
That's weird.
我的裤子变短了
My pants shrank.
我想我发育了
I think I hit puberty.
不该说出来的
我得买新裤子了
I gotta get new pants.
等等  为什么我脑子里的声音这么大?
Wait. Why is the voice in my head so loud?
怎么回事
What
你没事吧?
Oh! Are you okay?
什么?
What?
我为什么会出那么多汗?
Why am I so sweaty?
你为什么出那么多汗?
Why are you so sweaty?
因为我在发育
It's a puberty thing.
我也不知道自己为什么那么说  我没有在发育
I don't know why I said that. I'm not going through puberty.
我是说  我已经成熟了
I did, but I'm done.
我现在是个男人
I'm a man.
你也是新来的  对吧?  这点我们一样
So you're, like, new here, right? We got that in common.
没错  这是其中一点
Yeah, that's one thing.
真棒  对  我叫迈尔斯
Cool, yeah. I'm Miles.
我叫格温达
I'm G-Waaaanda.
等等  你叫格温达?
Wait, your name is Gwanda?
没错  非洲名  我是南非人
Yes, it's African. I'm South African.
我从小在这里长大  所以没口音
No accent though 'cause I was raised here.
快使出搭肩膀那招  趁她还没走
Do the shoulder touch now! Before she walks away!
为什么感觉这么慌?
Why is this so scary?
是我在做慢动作  还是就是这种感觉
Am I doing this in slow motion or does it just feel that way?
逗你的  我叫温达  没有“格” 开个玩笑
I'm kidding. It's Wanda. No G. That's crazy.
嘿
Hey.
好吧  那么  我们回头见
OK then. I'll see you around.
回见
Oh. See you.
抱歉  -嘿
- Sorry. Um... - Hey.
怪了  -放开我好吗?
- Oh, crap. - Can you let go, please?
我不行  -别乱动  没关系
- I can't let go. - Ow! Ow! Calm down. It's fine.
迈尔斯  放开
Miles, let go!
我也想  这都要怪青春期
I'm working on it. It's just puberty!
我想你对青春期的定义有些误解  听着  放轻松
I don't think you know what puberty is! Just relax.
好吧  我有个主意  -很好
Okay, I have a plan. - Great.
我要使劲扯了  -这是个愚蠢的主意
- I'm gonna pull really hard. - That's a terrible plan.
一  -别那么做
- One. - Don't do this.
二  三
- Two. - Three!
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
是的  特别高兴
Sure. Total pleasure.
没人看到  没关系
No one saw. It's ok.
没人知道  没人知道
No one knows, no one knows.
大家都知道了
Everyone knows.
大家都知道了  他们在嘲笑我
Everyone knows! They're talkin' 'bout me.
他们都看到了
They saw everything!
他知道  她知道  他们都知道
He knows. She knows. They know.
哇  他长得可真高
Wow, she's super tall.
他为什么在笑?  我现在成怪胎了吗?
Why is he smiling? Am I the weird guy now?
我在干吗?
What am I doing?
那家伙真是个怪人
That guy's such a weirdo.
我怎么停下来?
How do I stop?
他们能听到我的心声?
Can they hear my thoughts?!
我的心声怎么会那么大声?
Why are all my thoughts so loud?!
嘿  我知道你昨晚溜出去了  莫拉莱斯
Hey! I know you snuck out last night, Morales.
装傻
Play dumb!
谁是莫拉莱斯?
Who's Morales?
也别那么傻
Not that dumb!
嘿
Hey!
好了  好了  没事了
Okay, okay. You're okay.
没事了
You're okay.
安保主管
没事了
You're okay.
他找不到你的
He'll never find you.
安保主管
他找不到你的
He'll never find you.
不是吧
No.
安保
你在我办公室里做什么?  莫拉莱斯  快开门
What are you doing in my office Morales?! Morales! Open up!
♪ Oh, Spider-bells Goblin smells ♪
为什么会这样?
Why is this happening?
♪ Spider-buggy blew a tire ♪
他的声音很好听
He's got a nice voice.
♪ Spidey-bells, Spidey-bells ♪
快开门
Open up!
别再粘着了
Stop sticking!
千万别松开  迈尔斯
Keep sticking, Miles! Oh!
霍夫施塔特提出了
Hofstadter is suggesting...
他提出了
...is that we...
我们都应该
...look on the...
好吧
Okay.
我的房间
My room!
《蜘蛛侠的真实生活》
为什么会这样?
"Why is this happening?"
别再粘着了
"Please stop sticking."
千万别松开
"Please keep st..."
等等  等等
Wait! Wait!
怎么可能有两个蜘蛛侠?
How could there be two Spider-Men?
不可能有两个蜘蛛侠
There can't be two Spider-Men.
可能吗?
Can there?
《两个蜘蛛侠》
拜托  艾伦叔叔  快接电话
Come on Uncle Aaron. Pick up. Pick up.
我是艾伦  我要出城几天  回来再打给你  再见
Yo, it's Aaron. I'm outta town for a few days. Hit you when I'm back. Peace.
不  不  不  不  这不可能
No nononono. It's not possible.
只是在发育
It's just puberty.
那是只普通的蜘蛛  我是个普通的男孩儿
It's a normal spider and I'm a normal kid!
好
All right!
当天晚上
迈尔斯正在寻找答案
我得找人聊聊
I gotta tell someone.
是你想多了  迈尔斯  你想多了
You're being crazy Miles. You're being crazy.
找到那只蜘蛛  一切就清楚了
Find the spider. You'll see.
是只普通蜘蛛
It's a normal spider.
感觉简直普通得不能再普通了
It's, like, boring how normal this spider is.
我就在这儿
I'm right here.
为什么偏偏是我?
Why is this happening to me?
慢点  我这是在做什么?
Slow down! What am I doing?
在那边
Way over there.
你跟我一样
You're like me.
迈尔斯  小心
Miles. Look out.
我不想当英雄
I don't wanna be a hero.
迈尔斯
Miles.
诺曼  你听我说
Norman, listen to me.
蜘蛛侠?
Spider-Man?!
我不能让你打开通往另一个时空的大门
I cannot let you open a portal to another dimension.
布鲁克林承受不了这个
Brooklyn is not zoned for that.
这不是我能决定的
It's not up to me.
那是绿恶魔吗?
Is that Green Goblin!?
你为什么不能放弃?
Why won't you quit?!
因为我不想布鲁克林被黑洞吞噬
I don't know I guess I like Brooklyn not being sucked into a black hole.
我还是先走为妙
I think I'm gonna go...
斯塔顿岛可以  反正布鲁克林不行
Staten Island maybe, Not Brooklyn!
不  不
No, no!
哇靠
Woah!!
现在怎么办?
What now?
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
知不知道你鞋带松了?
Did you know your shoes are untied?
嗯哼  -我穿的是连体服
- Uh-huh. - This is a onesie,
所以不用担心
so I don't really have to worry about it.
我以为我是唯一的  你和我一样
I thought I was the only one. You're like me.
我可不想
I don't want to be.
恐怕你没得选  孩子
I don't think you have a choice, kiddo.
我能理解你的困惑  相信我
Got a lot going through your head, I'm sure.
当然
Yeah...
你不会有事的  我可以帮你
You're gonna be fine. I can help you.
你等我一下  一会儿我教你两招
If you stick around, I can show you the ropes.
好的
Yeah.
我必须得赶在时空连续体崩塌之前
I just need to destroy this big machine real quick
毁掉那台机器
before the space-time continuum collapses.
别走开
Don't move.
一会儿见
See you in a bit.
他是怎么做到的?
How does he do that?
是在这儿吗?  不  不  在这儿
Is it here? No, no. Is here
好了  各位
All right, folks.
我总是搞错
I always get this wrong.
糟糕
Oh boy.
徘徊者
Prowler.
伙计 我正忙着呢
Man, I was in the middle of something.
心好累
I am so tired...
你还在生我的气吗?  我觉得你在生我的气
Are you mad at me? I feel like you're mad at me.
你就这点能耐?
Is that all you got?
真恶心
Uhh, so gross.
我应该上去帮他
I should go up there and help him!
开什么玩笑?  这怎么可能
Who am I kidding? I should not do that.
注意  蜘蛛侠来了
Watch out. Here comes the Spider-Man.
喜欢我的新玩具吗?
You like my new toy?
花了我不少钱  不过钱财乃身外之物  对吧?
Cost me a fortune, but, hey, can't take it with you, right?
你大老远跑来  观看我的试验
You came all this way. Watch the test.
这会是场超炫的灯光秀
It's a hell of a freaking light show.
你一定会喜欢的
You're gonna love this.
探针已激活
不  不  别这样  快停下
No! No, don't do this! Stop!
你不知道它能做什么  你会害死我们的
You don't know what it can do! You'll kill us all!
传送门正在开启  我看到了多个宇宙正在开启
The portal is opening. I see multiple dimensions opening!
三个  四个  五个不同的宇宙
That was 3... 4... and 5 separate dimensions
它们很不稳定  得马上停止
It's unstable... we should stop.
诺曼  你一般怎么处理头部创伤?
Norm, what's your take on head trauma?
我都提醒你了
I tried to warn you, pal.
警 告
绿恶魔  不  把他弄出来
Goblin, no! Get him out of there!
威尔逊  我们在哪里?
Wilson! Where are we?
真奇怪
Really weird.
威尔逊
Wilson!
嘿  你没事吧?
Hey! Are you okay?
我没事  我没事  只是需要休息一下
I'm fine, I'm fine. Just resting.
你还能站起来吗?-当然
- Can't you get up? - Yeah.
我每次都能站起来
Yeah, yeah I always get up...
咳嗽可能不是好兆头
The coughing's probably not a good sign.
找到他  快
Find him. Now.
听着  我们得合作  时间不多了
Listen, we gotta team up here, we don't have that much time...
只有这把重载钥匙能阻止对撞机
This override key is the only way to stop the collider.
荡过去  用这把钥匙  按下红色按钮  炸飞他
Swing up there, use this key, push the button and blow it up.
你得把脸藏起来
You need to hide your face.
别告诉任何人你是谁
You don't tell anyone who you are.
谁都不能说  他能撬开任何人的嘴
No one can know. He's got everyone in his pocket.
什么?  -如果他再次启动机器
-What?  - If he turns the machine on again,
你所知道的一切都会消失
everything you know will disappear.
你的家人  所以人
Your family, everyone.
所有人
Everyone.
答应我好吗
Promise me you'll do this.
我答应你
I promise.
去吧  毁了对撞机
Go. Destroy the collider.
我会去找你的
I'll come and find you.
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
墓碑
Tombstone.
试验到此结束
We're done with tests.
尽快准备好再启动一次
Get that thing ready to go again. And soon.
快点跑  这群家伙真没用
Run faster. These guys are weak.
本想说很高兴又见到你了  蜘蛛侠  可惜不是
I'd say it's nice to see you again, Spider-Man. But it's not.
嘿  金并  生意好吗?
Hey Kingpin. How's business?
很火爆哈
Booming. Ha!
很好  好吧  这样可不行
Nice. Aw, that's a no-no.
你这么做会在布鲁克林的下面撕开一个黑洞
This might open a black hole under Brooklyn.
不能冒这个险
It can't be worth the risk.
不是所有事都是为了钱  蜘蛛侠
It's not always about the money, Spider-Man.
你不想知道我看到了什么吗?
Don't you want to know what I saw in there?
等等
Wait.
我知道你想干什么
I know what you're trying to do,
这么做没用的
and it won't work.
他们已经死了
They're gone.
把尸体处理掉
Get rid of the body.
那是什么?
What was that?
杀了他
Kill that guy.
别粘着了
Stop sticking!
请勿倚靠车门  谢谢
Stand clear of the closing doors, please.
应该是班克斯风格的街头艺术
Yeah, I think it's a Banksy.
市民反映  纽约又一起神秘地震事件
New Yorkers are reporting sporadic
导致了本市多处断电
power outages in the wake of another strange seismic event...
警察  举起手来
Police! Put your hands up!
迈尔斯?
Miles? Miles?
你怎么不在学校?
Why aren't you at school?
没事了
Whoa, whoa, it's ok.
迈尔斯?  出什么事了?
Miles? ¿Qué te pasa?
是因为地震吗?
Is it the earthquake?
我今晚能留下吗?
Can I sleep here tonight?
迈尔斯  今天不是周末
Miles, it's a weeknight.
你应该待在学校的
You made a commitment to that school.
杰夫  他不舒服
Jeff, he's upset.
你当然能留下
Of course you can stay.
爸爸?  -怎么?
Dad? - Yeah?
你真的很讨厌蜘蛛侠吗?
Do you really hate Spider-Man?
是吧  我是说  身为一名警察
Yeah. I mean, with a vigilante, there is...
杰夫  亲爱的
Jeff, mi amor
怎么了?  是他问我的
What? He asked me.
你知道我对蜘蛛侠的看法
Baby, you know how I feel about Spider-Man. Come on.
你知道他很爱你
Tú sabes que él te quiere mucho.
所以才会这么严格  你懂的  对吧?
That's why he's tough on you. You know that, right?
妈妈  你有没有想过离开布鲁克林?
Mom, do you ever think about moving out of Brooklyn?
我们家的人从不逃避问题  迈尔斯
Our family doesn't run from things, Miles.
对  我知道
Yeah, I know.
那是怎么回事?
What's that about?
他正处于艰难期  杰夫
He's having a hard time, Jeff.
越是艰难  他越是应该坚持
When it gets hard, that's when he's gotta stick it out.
嘘  你应该更温柔一点
Shhhh. Tiene que mas suave.
插播一条特别消息
We interrupt this broadcast for a special report.
一则悲痛的消息
Sad news tonight.
我们的英雄蜘蛛侠  今天离开了我们
The hero known as Spider-Man has died
他的死与今天发生在布鲁克林的
after injuries related to another powerful earthquake
另一场神秘地震事件有关  经多方消息证实
in Brooklyn. Multiple sources are confirming
彼得·帕克  26岁的研究生
that Peter Parker, a 26-year-old grad student
兼职摄影师
and part-time photographer
在近十多年中  一直扮演着蜘蛛侠的角色
operated as Spider-Man for at least a decade.
♪ I'm not runnin' Runnin', runnin' ♪
♪ No, I'm not afraid Of the fall ♪
♪ I'm not scared... ♪
帕克家中还有他的妻子玛丽·简
He is survived by his wife, Mary Jane,
和他的婶婶梅·帕克
and his aunt, May Parker.
我们的英雄蜘蛛侠离开了我们
Our hero Spider-Man is gone.
♪ I'm not scared... ♪
我的丈夫彼得·帕克
My husband, Peter Parker,
他曾经是一个普通人
was an ordinary person.
他总是说谁都能成为面具后面的那个人
He always said it could've been anyone behind the mask.
他只是凑巧被蜘蛛咬了而已
He was just the kid who happened to get bit.
我会想念他的
I'm going to miss him.
是啊
Yeah.
我们以前可是朋友
We were friends you know.
如果不合身  我能来退吗?
Can I return it if it doesn't fit?
到最后  总会合身的
It always fits. Eventually.
一经售出
概不退换
这并不是他的本意
He didn't ask for his powers.
可他选择成为了蜘蛛侠
but he chose to be Spider-Man.
我最爱彼得的地方就是
My favorite thing about Peter
他让我们所有人都充满了力量
is that he made us each feel powerful.
我们每个人都有着属于自己的力量
We all have powers of one kind or another.
♪ Of the dark... ♪
我们以自己的方式
But in our own way.
扮演者蜘蛛侠
We are all Spider-Man.
我们需要你
And we're all counting on you.
他们需要我
They're counting on me.
应该不是特指你  只是个比喻而已
Probably not you specifically. I think it's a metaphor.
《蜘蛛侠的真实生活》
只有一个办法  比利
你必须跨出这一步
无论有多危险
我很抱歉  帕克先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Parker.
你给我的那把重载钥匙
That thing you gave me, that key
我可能把它弄坏了
I think I really messed it up.
我也想遵守约定
I wanna do what you asked.
我真的很想
I really do.
可是  对不起
But I'm sorry.
没有你
I'm not sure I'm the guy.
我一个人根本不行
I can't do this without you.
嘿  孩子
Hey! Kid!
我对他做了什么?
What did I do to him? Uh...
不
No...
你是谁?
Who are you?
好吧  各位  我们最后再来一次
All right, people, let's do this one last time.
《超凡蜘蛛侠》
我叫做彼得·本杰明·帕克
My name is Peter B. Parker.
我被一只受过辐射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在接下来的二十二年里
And for the last 22 years,
我认为我是这世上唯一的蜘蛛侠
I thought I was the one and only Spider-Man.
忙碌的一天
What a day...
剩下的你们肯定都知道了
I'm pretty sure you know the rest.
我救过这座城市  坠入过爱河  还结了婚
You see, I saved the city, fell in love, I got married,
又救了几次城市  或许太多了
saved the city some more, maybe too much.
我的婚姻出现了危机  投资了一些糟糕的项目
My marriage got testy, made some dicey money choices.
市场形势大好  买买买
我的婚姻出现了危机  投资了一些糟糕的项目
My marriage got testy, made some dicey money choices.
小 蜘 蛛 餐 厅 真 恶 心
我的婚姻出现了危机  投资了一些糟糕的项目
My marriage got testy, made some dicey money choices.
千万别投以蜘蛛侠为名的主题餐厅
Don't invest in a spider-themed restaurant.
小 蜘 蛛 餐 厅 真 恶 心
千万别投以蜘蛛侠为名的主题餐厅
Don't invest in a spider-themed restaurant.
小蜘蛛餐厅
关门大吉
千万别投以蜘蛛侠为名的主题餐厅
Don't invest in a spider-themed restaurant.
就这样过去了十五年  吧啦  吧啦  吧啦  超级无聊
Then like 15 years passed. Blah, blah, blah. Super boring.
我摔断了脊背  脸撞在了无人机上
I broke my back, a drone flew into my face,
送走了梅婶婶
I buried Aunt May.
最后和我的妻子分开了
My wife and I split up.
但这一切我都沉着以对
But I handled it like a champion.
你知道吗
'Cause, you know what,
不管遭受多少次打击
no matter how many times I get hit,
我最终总是会爬起来
I always get back up.
我有大把的时间自我反省
And I got a lot of time to reflect and work on myself.
知道吗? 海马一旦结合就再也不会分开
Did you know that seahorses, that they mate for life?
你能想象吗?
Could you imagine?
一只海马见到了另一只海马
A seahorse seeing another seahorse
然后他们就成了
and then making it work?
她想要孩子  可是这吓坏我了
She wanted kids and it scared me.
我知道我伤了她的心
I'm pretty sure I broke her heart.
闪进  当时我正在家里做俯卧撑
Flash forward, I'm in my apartment doing pushups,
还有仰卧起坐  让自己变得更强
doing ab crunches, getting strong,
突然奇怪的事发生了
when this weird thing happened.
虽然我对奇怪的事已经见惯不怪
And I gotta say, weird things happen to me a lot.
可是这次的情况真的很奇怪
But this was real weird.
我还在纽约  可周围不太一样
You see I was in New York, but... things were different.
而且我死了
Also, I was dead.
还有一头金发
And blond.
我看起来简直完美
I was kind of perfect.
感觉就像在照镜子一样
It was like looking in a mirror.
我有种直觉
I have a feeling that the thing
带我来到这儿的东西
that brought me here
就是害死他的原因
was the thing that got him killed.
想知道接下来发生了什么吗?
You wanna know what happened next?
我也想知道
Me too.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你在哪儿干什么?
What are you doing over there?
别动  纽约警察
Freeze! P.D.N.Y.
站住
Stop!
这是在逗我吗?
Are you kidding me right now?
站住 站住
Stop! Stop!
我抓住了
I gotcha. I gotcha.
嘿  小子  放下尸体
Hey kid, drop the body!
嘿  小子  快过来
Hey kid! Get over here!
回头见  警官
See ya, officers!
不是吧
Oh come on
嘿  小子  别乱动  举起手  孩子
Hey kid! C'mon now! Put em' up, son!
再见
Adios?
救命  快让列车停下
Help! Somebody stop that train!
嘿  什么情况?
Oh, hey, what the...?
抱歉
Sorry
要死翘翘啦
I'm gonna die!
情况好像是一个打扮成蜘蛛侠的孩子
Looks like a child dressed like Spider-Man
拖着一个流浪汉的尸体在追赶列车
dragging a homeless corpse behind a train.
太好了  我没杀了你
Yes! I didn't kill you!
你是谁?
Who are you?
你又是谁?
你为什么想要杀我?
Why are you trying to kill me?
我没有  我是想要救你
I'm not! I'm trying to save you!
麻烦绕道走好吗?
Hey, maybe you guys can go around?
好吧  谢谢配合
All right. Thanks, New York.
什么情况?
What was that?
那孩子电击了我
Kid electrocuted me
用他的手吗?
with his hands?
你和我一样
You're like me.
我有话要问你
I got some questions.
你为什么那么像彼得·帕克?
Why do you look like Peter Parker?
因为我就是彼得·帕克
Because I am Peter Parker.
那你怎么没死?  头发为什么不一样了?
Then why aren't you dead? And why is your hair different?
为什么你变老了?  还有你的体型
Why are you older? And why is your body
怎么变形了?
a different shape?
你是想说我胖是吧
Pretty sure you just called me fat.
不  不  只是
No, no you just
你也没帅到哪儿去  小子
You don't look so hot either, kid.
超级英雄不会买自己的周边
Most superheroes don't wear their own merch.
你是鬼魂吗?
Are you a ghost?
不是
No
你是僵尸吗?
Are you a zombie?
住嘴
Stop it
我是僵尸吗?
Am I a zombie?
别扯淡了
You're not even close
你来自另一个时空?
Are you from another dimension?
就像平行宇宙
Like a parallel universe
彼此相似但却又不相同
where things are like this universe but different?
你是那里的蜘蛛侠
And you're Spider-Man in that universe?
然后你穿越到了这里
But somehow traveled to this universe,
而你并不知道原因
but you don't know how?
你真的只是随便猜猜的?
Wow. That was really just a guess?
其实  我们在物理课上学过
Well, we learned about it in physics.
量子理论
Quantum theory.
这太酷了  那你就可以像彼得说的那样教我了
This is amazing. You can teach me just like Peter said he would.
在他生前
Before he died.
对  没错
Yeah, exactly.
好吧
Yeah, alright.
听着  我答应过他的
Look I made a promise to him.
我现在就来教你第一课  小子
Here's lesson number one, kid.
别光顾着听  要仔细看
Don't watch the mouth. Watch the hands.
彼得  我是认真的
Peter, seriously.
相信我  孩子  这样你会过得轻松些
Trust me, kid, this'll all make you a better Spider-Man.
嘿  你还好吗?
Hey, are you okay?
不  很不好
No I'm not.
你的身体怎么了?
What's going on with your body?
我的原子可能不太适应
I don't think my atoms are real jazzed
这个错误的时空
about being in the wrong dimension.
听着  我不是来应聘兼职
Look, I'm not looking for a side gig
做蜘蛛侠教练的
as a Spider-Man coach.
在我的世界我还有很多事情要处理
I got a lot going on in my dimension.
能力越大  责任就
With great power comes great...
别在我面前说那句话
Don't you dare finish that sentence.
别再说了  我受够了
don't do it. I'm sick of it.
想要我的意见?  做回个普通小孩吧
Want my advice? Go back to being a regular kid.
我根本没得选
I don't have a choice!
金并造了一架对撞机
Kingpin's got a supercollider.
他想要杀了我
He's tryin' to kill me.
等等  你刚才说什么?
Wait a second, what did you just say?
金并想要杀了我
Kingpin's trying to kill me.
谁关心这个?  对撞机在哪里?
Who cares about that? Where's the collider?
布鲁克林  菲斯克大楼下面
Brooklyn. Under Fisk Tower
再见
Goodbye!
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
等它再启动时  只要跳进去就能回家了
When it runs again, I'll just jump in and get back to my life
你不能重启对撞机
- You can't let them run it.
我的任务就是毁了它
I'm supposed to destroy it
阻止它再次启动  否则所有人都会死
so it never runs again or everyone's gonna die.
否则所有人都会死  他们每次都爱说这句话
Or everyone's going to die. That is what they always say.
但在“所有人都会死”之前总还会有点时间
But there's always a little bit of time before everybody dies,
这时就要看我的了
and that's when I do my best work.
你难道不需要这个吗?
Aren't you going to need this?
你有个小玩意儿  交给我
Ah you have a goober. Give it.
等等  不  没那么容易  他管它叫重载钥匙
Wait, no. Not so fast. He called it an override key.
总会有把漏洞钥匙  病毒钥匙  各种乱七八糟的钥匙
There's always a bypass key, a virus key, a who-cares key.
记都记不清
I can never remember,
所以索性叫它们小玩意儿  交给我
so I always call it a goober. Give it.
我需要它帮我摧毁对撞机
I need it to destroy the collider.
我需要它帮我回家
I need it to go home!
不  再逼我  我就吞了它
No! I'll swallow it, don't play with me!
什么?  - 我说
- What? - I said...
对撞机打开了入口  把我带到了这里
The collider created a portal that brought me here.
所以我得
And I have to get...
你把它搞坏?  - 不  本来就是坏的
Did you break this? - No, it broke.
我不记得发生了什么
I don't remember what happened.
看到没  所以我才不要孩子  简直太明智了
This is why I never had kids, this is why I never did that.
我们不能再做一个吗?
Can't we make another one?
不  这里没你什么事  多亏了你
No, we can't do anything. Thanks to you,
我得重复那个家伙的工作  去欧克马克斯再偷一次数据
I have to re-steal what your guy stole from Alchemax
做个新钥匙
and make another one of these.
如果你走之后我没能关掉对撞机
If I don't turn off the collider after you leave,
这座城市的每一个人
everyone in this city,
我的父母  我的叔叔  成千上万的人都会死
my parents, my uncle and millions of others, will die.
你打算就这么一走了之
And you're just gonna go home
把我一个人留在这儿面对这一切?
and leave me here to figure this out for myself?
你做得出这种事吗? 蜘蛛侠
- You good with that, Spider-Man?
对
- Yeah.
你蹲在那儿干什么?
What are you doing?
让你良心不安  有效果吗?
Making you feel guilty. Is it working?
怎么可能?  不  你看我
How could it...? No. Look at me.
像有效果的样子吗?
Does it look like it's working?
不  没有  当然没有
No. No, it's not...
不  不  不能让他得逞
Ahhh!!! No! No! Do not let him win!
好吧  孩子  你赢了
Alright kid you win.
走吧  我们没时间浪费了
C'mon, we don't have a second to lose.
我喜欢这汉堡  太好吃了
Mmm. I love this burger. So delicious.
我吃过的最好吃的汉堡之一
One of the best burgers I've ever had.
在我们那儿  这地方六年前就关门了
In my universe, this place closed six years ago.
真搞不懂  明明很好吃
I don't know why. I really don't.
你带钱了对吧? 我最近手头紧
You have money right? I'm not very liquid right now.
说正经事好吗?
Can we focus?
当然
Uh huh sure.
另一个彼得  -你不吃吗?
- The other Peter... - You gonna eat that?
我在听呢
I'm listening.
另一个彼得之前说过他会教我几招
The other Peter said he was going to be showing me the ropes.
你有什么蜘蛛侠窍门可以教我吗?
You got any Spider-Man tips you can tell me now?
多了去了
Yeah, I got plenty.
面具要消毒
Disinfect the mask.
穿紧身衣要扑点爽身粉
You're gonna wanna use baby powder in the suit,
尤其是关节部位
heavy on the joints.
你也不想出疹子  对吧?
You don't want any chafing, right?
还有别的吗?
Anything else?
没了  就这些
Nope, that was everything.
你这老师也太差劲了吧
I think you're going to be a bad teacher.
查查欧克马克斯在哪儿
Mhmm.. Look up where Alchemax is.
纽约哈德逊山谷的一家私人科技园区
A private technological campus in Hudson Valley, New York.
你可以教我怎么荡过去
You can teach me to swing on the way there.
我们不可能一路荡到哈德逊山谷  迈尔斯
I'm not swinging to the Hudson Valley, Miles.
尤其是吃了汉堡大餐之后
Not after a hearty burger breakfast.
节省点体力  你会感谢我的
Keep your legs fresh. You're gonna thank me later.
♪ I can see a new horizon ♪
♪ Underneath the blazing sky ♪
♪ I'll be where the eagle's Flying higher... ♪
还有别穿斗篷
And it's a no on the cape.
我觉得还挺酷的
I think it's cool.
快脱掉  丢死人了
Take that off. It's disrespectful.
蜘蛛侠不穿斗篷
Spider-Man doesn't wear a cape.
我们要怎么重复彼得的工作?
So how do we retrace Peter's steps?
这是个好问题
That's a good question.
如果我是我  我会怎么做?
What would I do if I were me?
有了
Got it.
第一步  先潜入实验室
Step One: I infiltrate the lab.
第二步  找到首席科学家的电脑
Two: Find the head scientist's computer.
那位推自行车的女士就是
That lady with the bike is the head scientist.
我在学校的纪录片里见过她
I saw her in this documentary.
很好  第三步  暂时抛开性别歧视
Cool! Step Three: I reexamine my personal biases.
第四步  黑进她的电脑
Step Four: I hack the computer.
其实也不算黑进去  应该是
It's not technically hacking. It's kinda
行了  别打断我思路
Not now. I just lost my train of thought.
第五步  下载重要信息
Step Five: Download the important stuff.
看到我就知道
I'll know it when I see it.
第六步  从餐厅抓一个面包圈  然后拔腿就跑
Step Six: I grab a bagel from the cafeteria and run.
那我要干吗?
So what am I doing?
第七步  你在这里把风  非常重要
uh Step 7: You stay here, you're lookout. Very important.
听着  伙计  你得教我蜘蛛侠的技能
Look, man. You gotta teach me how to do Spider-Man stuff
这样我才能帮你
or I won't be able to help.
好的
Alright...
学着点  小子  一会儿我来考你
Watch and learn, kid, I'll quiz you later!
为什么我要和
Why did I get stuck with
这个又老又挫的流浪蜘蛛侠在一起?
the janky, old, broke hobo Spider-Man?!
新技能
That's new.
金并
Kingpin!
我在干吗?  我在干吗?
What am I doing? What am I doing?
彼得
Peter!
你在这儿干吗?
Yeah, what are you doing here?!
金并来了  你往边上去点儿
Kingpin's here! Just move over!
拜托  你压着我的脚了
C'mon! You're stepping on my foot!
往你的右边挪一下
Move a little to your right
赶紧爬出去
Go back outside!
不  我不能该眼睁睁看着蜘蛛侠遇难
No! I can't sit there and let Spider-Man die
自己却什么都不做
without doing anything about it.
我不会再那么做
I'm not doing that again.
干吗?
What?
我遇到的人大都想要杀了我
Most people I meet in the workplace try to kill me,
所以换种画风也不错
so you're a nice change of pace.
菲斯克先生
Uh, Mr. Fisk!
请看数据  我知道你不理解
Look at this data. I know you can't really understand it,
但这些都是好消息
but these are really good numbers.
我知道密码了
And... I got the password!
菲斯克先生  如果本周再次重启对撞机
Mr. Fisk. If we fire again this week
布鲁克林的下面就会产生一个黑洞
there could be a black hole under Brooklyn.
您看这个  还有这个
You see this? And this?
这就是多重宇宙
This is multiple dimensions
开始互相挤压的迹象
beginning to crash into each other.
这是蜘蛛侠剧情的老套路
This is pretty standard Spider-Man stakes.
要慢慢习惯  看好了
You get used to it. Watch this.
他会说“我再给你24小时”
He's gonna say, "You've got 24 hours."
我再给你24小时
You've got twenty-four hours.
这么做的话可能会导致连续时空里出现裂缝
What this means is that there could be a rupture in the space time continuum.
太糟了
Ooh. That's bad.
其实她说的句句都很糟糕
Actually, everything she said was bad.
是我轻敌了
I was lying before.
好吧  等等  还有别的数据
OK hold on, let me show you some more data
你在干吗? 伙计
What're you doing, bud?
我动不了
I can't move!
好了  放松你的手指
Okay, relax your fingers.
我们没时间了  放手  放掉就好  进入状态
We don't have time. Just let go. Be in the moment.
我在状态里  而且是糟糕的状态
I am in the moment, it's a terrible moment!
我不是在拒绝
I'm not refusing
别再找借口了
No more excuses!
我只是需要时间
I just need more time.
他们就在外面  你会被发现的
They're right there. They're gonna see you.
迈尔斯  你得赶紧松手
Miles, you gotta unstick.
你一般怎么做才会放松?
What do you do to relax?
放松  好的
Relax. Okay...
♪ Needless to say, I... ♪
还有这种操作
Oh, for crying out loud.
♪ Callin' it quits
Now, baby, I'm a wreck ♪
♪ You're a wreck, ooh... ♪
小屁孩  果然不靠谱
Teenagers, just the worst
迈尔斯  你去哪儿了?
Miles? Where did you go?
我就在这儿
I'm right here.
在哪儿? 我看不到你
Where? I can't see you.
我就在你面前  蜘蛛侠能隐身吗?
I'm right in front of you. Can Spider-Man turn invisible?
在我们那儿不行
Not in my universe.
啊  你戳到我眼睛了
Ow! You just poked me in my eye!
真是不可思议  像是打不过就闪的本能
This is incredible some kind of fight or flight thing.
什么意思?
What's that?
把密码记下来  D-g-f-a-m-p-e-s-a-n-d
Remember this password: Dgfampesand
慢点  彼得
Slow down, Peter!
-4-$-3-5-8-7-6-5-3-4-5-4-5-3-5.
我得写下来
I need to write it down!
接着下载设计图纸
and download the schematic
我要怎么做?
How do I do that?!
然后看我使出美男计
While I turn on the charm.
蜘蛛侠?
Spider-Man?
嘿  刚才没看到你
Oh, hey. Didn't see you there...
好吧  我有点被吓着了
Okay, I'm kinda freaking out right now.
我是说  你应该死了才对
I mean, You're supposed to be dead.
没想到吧  好吧  这样可不行  我不习惯
Surprise! Okay. That's a no-no. We don't like that.
真是太神奇了
This is fascinating.
好吧  那是我的脸
Okay, that's my face.
一个完全不同的彼得·帕克
An entirely different Peter Parker.
好吧  有点小肚腩  可能是因为空间扭曲
OK, a little bit of a gut, perhaps from dimensional warping.
对  对  对  穿越前我比现在瘦多了
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. I was way flatter before I warped.
穿越时空似乎会造成细胞恶化
Travel through the multiverse appears to have deteriorated...
接下去是什么?
Ah what was the rest?!
你多大了? 你看上去不超过35岁
How old are you? You don't look a day over 35!
他们说我疯了！他们说我疯了！
They said I was crazy! They said I was crazy!
你给他们看看你没疯
You showed 'em you're not crazy.
这可能会有点疼
This might pinch a little.
我知道  我只需要取一些样本
I know, I just need to get these samples.
好吧
Yeah, ok.
就不能整理下桌面吗  女士
Organize your desktop, lady!
哇  体内的细胞正在发生衰变
Wow. Just complete cellular decay.
我从来没见过这种情况
I've never seen anything like this.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
把数据连窝端走
I'm just taking the whole thing.
很明显  你出故障了
And obviously you've been glitching.
故障? 不  为什么这么说?
Glitching? No. Why would you even say that?
你在这个空间待太久了
If you stay in this dimension too long,
你的身体正在瓦解
your body's gonna disintegrate.
知道这会有多疼吗? 彼得·帕克
Do you know how painful that would be, Peter Parker?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
你根本想象不到
You can't imagine.
而我迫不及待想要见证那一刻
And I, for one, can't wait to watch.
你叫什么名字来着?
What did you say your name was?
奥利维亚·奥克塔维厄斯博士
Doctor Olivia Octavius.
我猜你的朋友是不是都叫你章鱼博士?
Can I assume that your friends call you Doc Ock?
我朋友都叫我丽芙
My friends actually call me Liv.
我的敌人才叫我章鱼博士
My enemies call me Doc Ock.
这儿交给我  快跑
I got this! Run!
你在和谁说话?
Who are you talking to?
我能搞定
I got it!
你搞得定吗? 彼得
Oh, you got it Peter?
我稳得住  伙计
I got it handled buddy!
一切尽在掌握之中
Everything is fine!
好吧  情况有点失控
Okay this is a little bit bad.
你废话还真多
Oh, you're chatty!
快走
Gotta go.
我想我快坚持不住了
And this is the moment that I'm losing the fight.
好吧  告诉你个好消息  我们不需要显示器
Alright, let me tell you the good news. We don't need the monitor.
彼得
Peter!
你怎么没告诉我  你还有个会隐身的朋友
You didn't tell me you had an invisible friend!
把电脑给我好吗? 年轻人
Could you give me that back, young man?
彼得
Peter!
这是私人财产
It's proprietary.
这种情况还是隐身比较好
Wow. This'd be a good time to turn invisible.
没错
- Yep.
好吧  那你怎么还不隐身
Ok, not going to turn invisible.
挑一个面包圈  表现得自然一点
Selecting a bagel... act super normal...
蜘蛛侠?
Spider-Man?
说来你也不信  很多人都会认错
You know it's funny I get that a lot.
嘿
- Hey.
蜘蛛侠?
Spider-Man?
嘿  举起手来
Hey! Hands Up!
好了  交换一下
Now we do a switchy-switchy.
什么?
What?
给我回来  你们想去哪里? 他偷了面包圈
Get back here! Where do you think you're going? He took a bagel!
好了  准备好荡起来  就像我教你的那样
Alright time to swing, just like I taught you!
你什么时候教过我?
When did you teach me that?
也对  我只是开个玩笑  增进感情
I didn't! It's a little joke for team building!
嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey! Hey! Hey!
准备好了吗?
Alright, you ready?
当然没有
Of course I'm not ready!
我还做不到
Whoa, whoa, I can't do this yet!
大家都知道  一个人在生死关头
Everybody knows that the best way to learn
可以做到许多本来做不到的事
is under intense life-threatening pressure.
拜托  拜托
C'mon, c'mon!
哦  不好
Uh oh.
你在下面做什么?
What are you doing down there?!
我跑得比荡得快
I run better than I swing!
你得荡起来  不然他们会抓住你的  这就是你想学的
You gotta swing or they'll catch you! This is what you wanted!
哦  不
Uh-oh.
快回来  小家伙
Come back, little boy!
以胯部为准线  瞄准目标位置
Aim with your hips! Look where you want it to hit.
肩膀放平  别忘了后续动作
Square your shoulders. Don't forget to follow through!
重心在后脚时不要发射
Don't shoot off your back foot.
太多了记不住
That's too many things!
那就别管我说的
Then stop listening to me!
这是你今天给的最有用的建议
That's the best idea you've had all day!
漂亮  迈尔斯
Nice Miles!
我做到了
I'm doing it!
很好  你做到了  轻按两下松开  然后再发射一次
Good, you're doing it! Double tap to release and thwip it out again.
懂了
Okay.
发射  然后松开  发射  松开
Thwip. And release. And thwip. Release.
发射  然后松开
Thwip. And release.
悟性不错
You're a natural.
发射  松开  找到节奏了吗?
Thwip. Release. Feel the rhythm?
再松开
Woohoo! And release.
很不错  迈尔斯
Good, Miles!
我想说  你超酷的  伙计
I gotta say, you're amazing man!
我们是团队了
We're a little team!
我是当年实力不减的老师
Me as the teacher who could still do it.
你资质不错  但和我当年比还差点
You as the student who can do it, just not as good.
真为我们骄傲  你有什么想对我说的吗?
I'm proud of us. Is there something you want to say to me?
彼得
Peter!
搞什么?
What the...
谁干的?
Who did that?
嘿  伙计们
Hey guys.
格温达?
Gwanda?
是格温才对
It's Gwen, actually.
你认识她? 真是不错
Oh, you know her? Very cool.
我来自另一个时空
I'm from another dimension.
我是说  除了另一个还有一个
I mean, another-another dimension.
好吧  各位  我们再从头来一次
All right, people. Let's start at the beginning one last time.
《蜘蛛侠格温》
好吧  各位  我们再从头来一次
All right, people. Let's start at the beginning one last time.
我叫做格温·史黛西
My name is Gwen Stacy.
我被一只受过辐射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在接下来的两年里
And for the last two years,
我成为了唯一的女蜘蛛侠
I've been the one and only Spider-Woman.
剩下的你们都知道了
You guys know the rest.
我加入了乐队
I joined a band.
救了我爸爸
Saved my dad.
可我却没能救下我最好的朋友
I couldn't save my best friend,
彼得·帕克
Peter Parker,
所以我发誓要救其他人
so now I save everyone else.
于是我决定再也不交朋友了
And I don't do friends anymore,
避免一切干扰
just to avoid any distractions.
突然有一天  奇怪的事发生了
And one day this weird thing happened.
这次的情况真的很奇怪
...and I mean, like, really weird.
我穿越到了上个星期
I was blown into last week.
一点都不夸张  我回到了纽约  可不是我的纽约
Literally. I landed in New York. But not my New York.
这是本月三州地区发生的第二次地震
...this is the second earthquake in the Tri-State area this month.
幸运的是
Lucky for these folks,
蜘蛛侠出现了
Spider-Man was there to save the day.
我的蜘蛛直觉告诉我得去愿景学校
My Spider-sense told me to head to Visions Academy.
是你们早到了
you guys are early.
我也不知道为什么  直到遇上了你
I wasn't sure why until I met you
我喜欢你的发型
I like your haircut.
你还好意思说
You don't get to like my haircut
我们走
Let's go.
到底有多少蜘蛛侠?
How many more spider people are there?
自己去动漫展上看吧
Save it for comic-con!
动漫展是什么?
What's Comic-Con?
受死吧  蜘蛛侠
You're dead Spider-Man.
威尔逊  你在做什么?
Wilson, what are you doing?
瓦内莎
Vanessa.
理查德  快走
Richard, c'mon...
瓦内莎  理查德  不
Vanessa! Richard! No!
别往后看  亲爱的  没事的  没事的
Don't look back honey. It's okay. It's okay.
我明明杀了蜘蛛侠
I killed Spider-Man.
为什么又多出来两个?
Why did I just see two more?
准确说是三个
There's three, actually.
不  这是好事  非常非常好
No, this is good. This is very, very good.
这意味着你的目的达到了
This means you get what you want.
我的对撞机起作用了
It means my collider works.
现在我们要做的就是  灭掉那几只蜘蛛
All we have to do is kill a couple of Spiders.
然后你的家人就能回到你的身边
And the collider will bring your family back.
想要多少就有多少
As many families as you want.
明天启动我的对撞机
Tomorrow at my collider.
是我们的对撞机
Our collider.
是他弄坏的吗?
He broke this?
对  他也觉得很不好意思
Yeah. He's actually really embarrassed about it,
所以就当没这事好吗?
so just keep it between us, okay?
我知道哪里能做个新的
I know where we can make a new one.
这次不会再让他弄坏了
And we won't let him break it this time.
你朋友的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your friend.
谢谢你  迈尔斯
Thanks, Miles.
我知道这有多艰难
I know how hard this is.
要一个人面对这一切
To have to figure this stuff out on your own.
知道自己不是一个人感觉还不错
It's kinda nice not being the only Spider-person around.
是啊
Yeah.
如果哪天你愿意交朋友了
If you ever decide to do friends again,
我可以给你留个位置
I could always open up a slot.
到时候我会告诉你的
I'll keep you posted.
好的
Cool.
不如我们还是走吧
We should probably go.
彼得  都已经到门口了
Peter, we're literally on the doorstep.
太糟了  太糟了  这主意太糟了
Bad idea, bad idea, this is a bad idea.
放轻松
Just relax.
感谢你们的关心
You guys are all very sweet,
但今天不接待粉丝了  谢谢
but no more fans today, please.
我还没做好心理准备
I'm not ready for this.
彼得
Peter...
嘿  梅婶婶
Hey, Aunt May.
我知道这听起来有些疯狂
So this is gonna sound crazy,
不过  我其实是来自
but I'm pretty sure that I'm from an...
另一个时空
an alternate dimension.
没错
Yeah.
你看起来很累  彼得
You look tired, Peter.
好吧  我确实很累
Well, I am tired.
有点苍老  而且还丰满了
And older. And... thicker.
对  已经有人说过了
Yeah, I've heard that already.
天啊  这个是宽松裤吗?
Oh jeez, are those sweatpants?
没错  就是宽松裤
Yup. That's what they are.
彼得走的时候
I was there,
我就在现场
when it all happened.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
你又是从哪个空间来的?
And what dimension are you from?
布鲁克林
Brooklyn.
彼得有没有什么地方能让我们重做一下这个?
Did Peter have a place where we could make another one of these?
是个小玩意儿
A goober.
跟我来
Follow me.
好吧  我也有这么个地方
Oh, yeah, I got one of these, too.
存放装备的小屋子
A little, old shed where I keep my Spider-gear.
这地方也太能装了
I mean, this place is pretentious.
伙计  你那儿也和这里一样吗?
Whoa. Dude, was yours anything like this?
差不多吧
Mine was like this,
不过没有吉普车和飞机
but take away the jeep, the plane.
想象一下是这儿的缩小版  再多两个床垫
Imagine it way smaller. Imagine a futon.
现在的年轻人真是的
I feel sad for this guy.
嘿  彼得
Hey, Peter.
这不是斗篷吗
I think this is a cape.
彼得知道他的使命有多危险
Peter knew how dangerous the job was.
可他也知道这世上唯一能阻止那家伙的
But he figured the only one who could stop this guy
只有蜘蛛侠
was Spider-Man.
金并知道我们会去找他
Kingpin knows we're coming.
可惜我们寡不敌众
We're going to be outnumbered.
那可不一定
Don't be so sure.
你们可能会用到这个
You might need these.
你们以为只有你们想到来这儿吗?
You think you're the only people who thought to come here?
嘿  伙计们
Hey fellas.
他是黑白的吗?
Is he in black and white?
哪里来的风? 这里可是地下室
Where is that wind coming from? We're in a basement.
不管到哪儿  冷风总是相随
Wherever I go, the wind follows.
而这风  终将幻化成雨
And the wind, it smells like rain.
大家好  你们好吗? 很高兴认识你们
Hi guys! Konichiwa! Hajimemashita yoroshuku?
敢不敢再诡异一点
This could literally not get any weirder.
还有更诡异的
It can get weirder.
我刚洗了手  所以它才是湿的
I just washed my hands. That's why they're wet.
没别的原因
No other reason.
你们和我一样
You're like me.
《蜘蛛侠格温》
《蜘猪侠》 《潘妮·帕克》 《暗影蜘蛛侠》
暗影蜘蛛侠
我叫做彼得·帕克
My name is Peter Parker.
我叫做潘妮·帕克
My name is Peni Parker.
潘妮  帕克
我叫做潘妮·帕克
My name is Peni Parker.
我叫做彼得·波克
My name is Peter Porker.
蜘猪侠
我叫做彼得·波克
My name is Peter Porker.
我被一只受过辐射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
我被一只受过辐射的猪咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive pig.
在我的宇宙  现在是1933年
In my universe, it's 1933,
我是名私家侦探
and I'm a private eye.
我爱喝布鲁克林特饮  蛋蜜乳
I like to drink egg creams,
也喜欢打击纳粹  非常喜欢
and I like to fight Nazis. A lot.
机甲蜘蛛二号
也喜欢打击纳粹  非常喜欢
and I like to fight Nazis. A lot.
我来自3145年的纽约
I'm from New York in the year 3145.
机甲蜘蛛二号
我来自3145年的纽约
I'm from New York in the year 3145.
我爸的机器人里住着一只蜘蛛
I have a psychic link with a spider
我和它有心灵感应
who lives inside my father's robot.
我们是一辈子的好朋友
And we're best friends. Forever.
有时我会让火柴一直燃烧到指尖
Sometimes I let matches burn down to my fingertips
只是为了能有点感觉
just to feel something, anything.
我是《嗥叫日报》的摄影师
I'm a photographer for the Daily Beagle.
工作时间我会像狗狗一样
When I'm not pooching around, I'm working like a dog,
到处挖掘劲爆新闻
trying to sniff out the latest story.
我唱歌跳舞
♪ I frolic and I dance ♪
边跳边扭屁股
♪ And I do this With my pants ♪
好了  可以了
Ok, enough!
那么  你们是怎么来的?
So, uh, how did you get here?
好吧  这可就说来话长了
Well, it's kind of a long story.
或许也没那么长
Maybe not that long.
现在我们只想回家
And now we're just trying to find a way home.
回家的唯一方法就是跳进那个对撞机
The only way home is back through that collider gizmo.
唯一的问题就是
The only trouble is...
得有个人留下来毁了那机器
One of us has to stay behind and destroy it.
我留下来
- I'll do it. - I'll do it.- I'll do it.
不  不  不  你们不明白
No, no, no, you don't get it.
不明白什么?
Don't get what
你们不能留在这儿  如果留在这儿  你们会死的
None of you can stay here. If you stay here, you'll die.
应该由我来关掉那机器
I'm the guy who's gonna turn it off.
我会等你们都回去之后再动手
And I'm gonna get you all home before I do.
我答应过他的  所以我必须做到
Look, I made a promise. So I have to keep it.
你是哪位?
Who are you again?
这是迈尔斯
This is Miles.
他将会拯救平行宇宙
And he's gonna save the multiverse.
没错
Yeah man.
这小子会隐身术  看好了  他现在就能隐形
This kid can turn himself invisible! Watch this, he can do it... now!
我不能说隐就隐
I can't do it on command
他不能说隐就隐  但还是很酷
He can't do it on command. But it is cool.
让他们看看电击  迈尔斯
Show them the zappy thing, Miles.
我不能说来就来
I can't do it on command
他不能说来就来
He can't do it on command.
但他还有其他技能  比如什么来这?
But he can do so much more. What else do you do?
只有这两样
Just those two things
Just those two things.
伙计
Oh, man.
听着  我见过他的技能  他很有潜力
Look, I've seen him in action. He's got potential.
我想他能送我们回家
I think he's gonna get us home.
好吧  年轻人
Okay, little fella,
金并会派很多坏蛋去找你
Kingpin's gonna send a lot of mugs after ya.
各个都很难缠  真正的大块头
I'm talkin' hard boys, real biscuit boxers.
你能一次性搞定他们吗?
Can you fight them all off at once?
其实我还没和别人交过手
Well, I, I haven't actually fought anyone.
出其不意
Surprise attack!
你能在交火时重新组装主机吗?
Can you re-wire a mainframe while being shot at?
你说什么?  -让我看看
Can I what? - Show me!
出其不意
Surprise attack!
你能像舞蹈家那样优雅地在半空回荡吗?
Can you swing and flip with the grace of a trained dancer?
你能切断自己的人性
Can you close off your feelings so you don't get crippled
不为自己 的暴力行为而感到内疚吗?
by the moral ambiguity of your violent actions?
你能帮你婶婶在相亲网站上注册账号
Can you help your aunt create an online dating profile
让她偶尔出去约个会吗?
so she can get out of the dang house once in a while?
当你闻到美食时  你能飘飘欲仙吗?
Can you float through the air when you smell a delicious pie?
什么?
What?
你够坚强吗?  -够无情吗?
- Can you be strong? - Ruthless?
够自律吗?  -我不知道  或许吧
- Disciplined? - I don't know. Maybe.
展现你的勇气  小兵
Show me some moxie, soldier
最重要的是  不管你被打趴下几次
Above all, no matter how many times you get hit,
你都能站起来吗?
can you get back up?
当蜘蛛侠倒地时
Because when a Spider-Man is on the floor
当你坚持不下去时
When you think you can't keep going
起来  迈尔斯
C'mon Miles.
你能做到的  -伙计们  行了
You can do this! - Guys, cool it.
起来  迈尔斯  你能做得到
Get up Miles! You can do it!
快起来  迈尔斯
Get up Miles!
拜托  迈尔斯  站起来
C'mon Miles! Get up!
你不能自欺欺人
You need to be more honest with yourself about this.
他还没准备好  这很明显
He's not ready. It's obvious.
行不通的  他只是个孩子
There's no way. He's just a kid.
如果他不行
If he can't do this,
我们就得留下替他完成任务
we have to stay and do it for him.
他在那儿听得到我们说他
He's looking right at us while we talk about him...
迈尔斯?  迈尔斯?
Miles? Miles?
看到没? 他真的会隐身
See that? He can uh, turn invisible...
♪ When it gets dark Outside ♪
♪ In you I confide ♪
爸爸
你有一条新语音消息
♪ You help me face my demons I won't hide... ♪
迈尔斯  你怎么回事?
Miles, what is going on with you?
大家都没你的消息  我们不知道你是怎么回事
Nobody's heard from you. We don't know what's going on.
如果你有事瞒着我们  赶紧坦白
If you're hidin' something from us, you need to come clean.
马上打给我
You call me back. Now.
他也不接我的电话
Aye... he's not answering me either.
我是艾伦  我要出城几天  回来再打给你  再见
It's Aaron. I'm outta town for a few days. Hit you when I'm back. Peace.
艾伦  我是杰夫
Aaron, it's Jeff.
听着  如果你有迈尔斯的消息  马上打给我
Look, I need you to call me if you've heard from Miles.
他对你总是那么信任
He has a soft spot for you,
我们和他失去联系了
and we haven't heard from him.
如果不是情况紧急  我是不会找你的
And you know I wouldn't reach out if this wasn't important.
希望一切都好
Hope you're good.
亲爱的艾伦叔叔
Dear Uncle Aaron.
我的去完成一件事  但我不知道能不能行
I gotta do something, and I don't know if I can do it.
我很害怕
I'm scared, man.
我受够了让所有人失望
I'm just tired of lettin' everybody down.
你是我唯一能够倾诉的人
You're the only one I can talk to.
我真希望你能在这儿
I just wish you were here.
你好  菲斯克先生
Hello, Mr. Fisk.
我从隧道那儿拿到了监控录像
I've got the security tapes from the tunnel right here.
只要他还在这儿  我会找到他的
If the kid's out there, I'll find him.
你了解我的  先生  我从不放弃
You know me, sir. I don't ever quit.
探测到热量
♪ Personal insanity They gotta like the ally ♪
♪ Turn it up Against the rally ♪
♪ You're running in While they're counting ♪
♪ Even score, got the tally Knock 'em off at the finale ♪
♪ Go, go! They don't want it, yeah ♪
♪ They don't want it, yeah ♪
这个是
This is...
紫色  -不是
- Purple. - No.
蓝色?  -不
- Blue? - No.
有迈尔斯的消息吗?
Has anyone heard from Miles?
他只是需要冷静一下  我了解那孩子
Look, he's just clearing his head. I know the kid.
他能搞得定
He's got what it takes.
我敢打赌他一定会跨过那个门槛
I bet you he's gonna come back through that door,
振作起来  准备好迎战
recharged and ready to fight.
我叔叔
My uncle!
嘿  你去哪儿了
Hey, where have you been
我叔叔艾伦  他  他  他是徘徊者
My Uncle Aaron, he he he'sthe Prowler!
慢慢说  慢慢说  迈尔斯
Ok, slow down. Slow down, Miles.
他替金并做事  他想要杀了我
He works for Kingpin, he tried to kill me!
这剧情也太简单粗暴了吧
This is a pretty hardcore origin story.
没事的  没事的  我们会弄明白的
It's okay, it's okay, we're gonna figure it out.
有人跟踪你吗?
Were you followed?
不  我想应该没有
No. I don't think so.
地方不错  真是温馨
- Cute place. Real homey.
好极了  是丽芙
Oh great, it's Liv.
我想我被跟踪了
I guess I was followed.
哦  不
Oh no...
快走  孩子
Get out of here kid.
你可闯大祸了  小子  太粗心了
You messed up big time kid. Very sloppy.
看看这些可怜的小蜘蛛
Mira todas estas arañitas.
让我猜猜  你是蝎子? 我们是蜘蛛  算是远亲
Let me guess, you're Scorpion? Well, we're the, uh... Spider-gang
你们介不介意到外面解决?
Would you mind taking this outside?
我们跳起舞来从不挑场子
We don't pick the ballroom we just dance.
那个就交给我吧
Oh, I think I'll be taking that.
小家伙  来吧  准备受死吧
Stand, niñito, dale. Prepárate a morir.
愚蠢的垫子
Man, stupid pillows.
都说让你们出去解决了
I said take it outside!
我来了
I got it!!
交给我  伙计
I got this buddy.
别碰那个孩子
Leave the kid alone!
不  不  不  不
No, no, no. No!
快离开  伙计
You gotta go, man.
所有车辆请注意  发生骚乱事件
All vehicles in the area, we have a disturbance
嫌疑人为蜘蛛们
involving multiple spider... people?
是的  这就去
Yeah, on my way!
把它交给我
Give me that thing!
别傻了  小子  快交给我
Don't be stupid, kid. Hand it over, now
你无路可逃了
Nowhere left to run.
迈尔斯?
...Miles?
艾伦叔叔
Uncle Aaron.
不  不  不
Oh no no no no...
求你了  艾伦叔叔
Please Uncle Aaron.
徘徊者
Prowler.
你还在等什么?  了结他
What are you waitin' for? Finish it.
快离开这儿
Get out of here!
不
No.
迈尔斯
...Miles...
艾伦叔叔  这都是我的错
...Uncle Aaron. This is my fault.
不  迈尔斯
No, Miles.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
是我骗了你  我想你崇拜我
I wanted you to look up to me.
是我让你失望了
I let you down, man. I let you down.
你是我们中最棒的  迈尔斯
You're the best of all of us, Miles.
你有属于自己的路
You're on your way.
你要坚持下去
Just keep going.
坚持下去
举起手来
Hands up!
快把你的手举起来
Put your arms up. Now!
转过来
Turn around.
嘿  嘿
Hey! Hey!!!
艾伦? 艾伦  不  不
Aaron? Aaron. No... No.
各单位注意  全境通缉一名新蜘蛛侠
All units. I want an APB on a new Spider-Man.
摆脱欲望
嘿  伙计  你没事吧?
Hey, bud. You okay?
我们都经历过  我失去的是我叔叔本
We've all been there. For me it was my Uncle Ben.
我失去的是我叔叔本杰明
For me it was my Uncle Benjamin.
我失去的是我爸爸
For me it was my father.
我失去的是我最好的朋友
For me it was my best friend.
迈尔斯  对我们而言最难接受的就是
Miles, the hardest thing about this job is
你不可能每次都救得了所有人
you can't always save everybody.
这都是我的错  你们不会理解
Look, it was my fault. You wouldn't understand.
迈尔斯  我们或许是这世上唯一能理解你的人
Miles, we're probably the only ones who do understand.
哦  不
Oh no...
♪ Who in here trying To start a riot? ♪
往那儿  往那儿
That way! That way!
另一边  另一边
Other way! Other way!
♪ Who that swinging In the air? ♪
嘿  伙计
Hey there!
你们这儿动物会说话吗?
Do animals talk in this dimension?
我可不想吓着他
'Cause I don't wanna freak him out.
♪ Let's stand up, stand up You better just fix your... ♪
怎么了?
What's going on?
再见  迈尔斯
Bye Miles.
迈尔斯  我是来道别的
Miles, I came to say goodbye.
可以在对撞机那儿道别
We can say goodbye at the collider.
你没明白  你得留在这儿
You're not getting it. You're staying here.
我必须去  这样你们才能回去
I need to be there. So you can all go home.
他们是要回家了  迈尔斯  我会一个人留下
They are going home, Miles. I'm the only one staying.
你要代替我?  留下的话你会死的
You're taking my place...? If you stay here you'll die.
我必须完成我该做的事
I'm doing what needs to be done.
我希望自己能亲口告诉你
I just wanted you to hear it from me.
那玛丽·简呢?
What about MJ?
不是所有的事都会有结果
Not everything works out, kid.
我需要小玩意儿
I need the goober.
请不要逼我从你那儿抢过来
Please don't make me take it from you.
这不公平  你去告诉他们我能做到
That's not fair! You've gotta tell them I can do this!
这不是他们的决定
It wasn't their decision.
我要让金并付出代价  你必须让我回去报仇
I gotta make Kingpin pay! You have to let me make him pay!
迈尔斯  你这样等于是去送死
Miles, you're gonna get yourself killed.
可我准备好了  我保证
But I'm ready, I promise
那你现在就来电我
Then venom-strike me right now.
或者隐藏自己  说隐就隐  然后从我身边走过
Or turn invisible on command so you can get past me.
听着  我知道你很想报仇  孩子
Look, I know how much you want this, kid.
可怜的小家伙
Poor little guy.
可你还没准备好
But you don't have it yet.
对不起
I'm sorry.
怎么才能知道自己准备好了
When will I know I'm ready
你不会知道  这是种信念
You won't. It's a leap of faith.
就这么简单  迈尔斯
That's all it is, Miles.
一种信念
A leap of faith.
迈尔斯
Miles.
迈尔斯  是爸爸
Miles, it's your dad.
请把门打开
Please open the door.
迈尔斯  我看得到你的影子
Miles, I can see your shadow moving around.
好吧  也对  我能理解  你还在生我气
Yeah, okay, I get it. I get it. You're still ignoring me.
我们能聊几句吗?
Look, can we talk for a minute?
有件事
Something...
有件事发生了
Something happened to...
有时候人与人之间会变得疏远  迈尔斯
Look, sometimes people drift apart, Miles.
我不希望这发生在我们身上  好吗?
And I don't want that to happen to us, okay?
我知道我一直没能
I know I don't always do what you need me to do
按照你希望的方式和你相处
or say what you need me to say.
可我看得到你身上的闪光点  这很了不起  所以我才会逼你
I see this spark in you. It's amazing. It's why I push you.
可这是你的人生
But it's yours.
不管你怎么选择  你都是最棒的
Whatever you choose to do with it, you'll be great.
回头记得打给我  好吗?  我爱你
Look call me when you can, ok? I love you.
这次你不用也说我爱你
You don't have to say it back though.
♪ 200 miles per hour With a blindfold on ♪
♪ Mama always asking "Where did I go wrong?" ♪
这么晚才到
Took you long enough.
♪ Ah, what's up, danger? ♪
我看得到你身上的闪光点
I see this spark in you.
这很了不起
It's amazing.
不管你怎么选择  你都是最棒的
Whatever you choose to do with it, you'll be great.
我们家的人从不逃避问题
Our family doesn't run from things.
你是我们中最棒的  迈尔斯  你有属于自己的路
You're the best of all of us, Miles. You're on your way.
坚持下去
Just keep going.
怎么才能知道自己准备好了?
When do I know I'm Spider-Man?
你不会知道
You won't.
就这么简单  迈尔斯
That's all it is, Miles.
一种信念
A leap of faith.
♪ Like, what's up, danger? ♪
（编剧注：Miles isn't falling through frame. He's RISING.）
我自己做的
Made 'em myself.
戴起来非常合身
They fit perfectly.
- ♪ Can't stop me now ♪
- ♪ Traveled 200 miles ♪
♪ I'm knockin' at your door And I don't really care ♪
- ♪ If you ain't done wrong ♪
- ♪ I said I got you now ♪
♪ Come on, what's up, danger? ♪
♪ Don't be a stranger ♪
♪ I'm right here at your door ♪
♪ I won't leave, I want more ♪
♪ What's up, danger? ♪
♪ Yeah, what's up, danger? ♪
♪ Can't stop me now ♪
♪ 'Cause I like high G's Sister, I might lose ♪
♪ I like it all on the edge Just like you, hey ♪
♪ I like tall buildings So I can leap off of 'em ♪
♪ I go hard with it No matter how dark it is ♪
♪ Come on, what's up, danger? ♪
《蜘蛛侠  迈尔斯·莫拉莱斯》
金并有一部私人电梯
Kingpin has a private elevator entrance
可以从顶楼直接通往对撞机那儿
from his penthouse to the collider below.
没想到还会有观众
Didn't count on having an audience.
开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
谢谢  很荣幸今晚能和大家一起
Thank you. It's nice to be with you this evening
纪念蜘蛛侠
to celebrate Spider-Man.
我们曾是很好的朋友  他就
He and I were very close. He was...
真是头猪
What a pig.
我在这儿呢
I'm right here.
等等  看看那些服务员的打扮
Hold on. Get a load of how the waiters are dressed.
真没品味  不过
It's in poor taste, but...
不会这么容易吧
It can't be that easy.
就是这么容易
It's that easy.
很感谢今晚玛丽·简·帕克
I just wanna thank Mary Jane Parker
可以出席我们的晚会  我们都会为你祈祷
for being here this evening. Our prayers are with you
玛丽·简?
MJ?
集中精神  那不是你的玛丽·简·彼得  懂吗?
Pay attention! It's not the same MJ, Peter. Ok?
抱歉  我马上回来
I'm sorry, I'll be right back
不  彼得  过来  相信我
No! Peter! Come here here! Trust me,
我也经历过  你要向前看
I've been there. You gotta move on, buddy.
就一下下  我只想和她
This will just take one sec. Let me just... Oh!
你好
Hello.
能不能麻烦给12号桌加点面包
Um, I just wondered if we could have some more bread at table twelve.
好的
Yeah.
我想说  我真的很抱歉
I'm just... I'm really sorry.
不用抱歉  只是面包而已
Oh, don't be sorry. It's just bread.
你需要我的时候  我没能出现
No, I wasn't there for you when you needed me.
我甚至都没尽力
And I didn't even try.
没关系  我想我该走了
That's fine. I should really get going
我知道我能做得更好
I know I could do better
如果我还有机会
if I just had another chance
我一定会给你  你值得拥有的那些面包
to give you the bread that you deserve.
你没事吧?
Are you ok?
女士  面包一会儿就送到
Ma'am we'll take care of that bread right now.
很高心能够和你聊天
It's been nice, uh, talking to you.
为了你  他们应该在这里铺满新鲜的面包
For you they should fill this place up with fresh bread.
你还好吧?  伙计
You alright, man?
是的  我很好
Yeah. Totally.
那就好  我们可没空管面包的事
OK good cause we are not getting any bread.
我只为家人无法看到今晚的情况感到遗憾
I'm just sorry my family can't see what we're doing tonight.
初始化初级点火序列
Initializing primary ignition sequence.
沉睡吧
Sleeeeeeep.
启动程序
Start the sequence.
上传瓦内莎·菲斯克和理查德·菲斯克的基因序列
Uploading Vanessa Fisk and Richard Fisk DNA sequence.
开始搜索空间匹配
Beginning scan for dimensional matches.
二级点火倒计时开始  五  四  三  二  一
Secondary ignition in 5... 4... 3... 2... 1.
彼得  你不必留下  我能搞定
Peter, you don't have to stay behind. I can do it.
没关系  我已经决定了
It's okay. I've made up my mind.
我会把小玩意儿插进去  控制光波
I'll put the goober in and take over the beam.
等你们都走了  我就炸了它
After you're gone, I'll blow it up.
祝你们好运
Good luck guys.
他们知道我们在这儿
They know we're here.
很搞笑又见面了  彼得
Nice to see you again, Peter.
我来掩护你
I got you covered!
这些家伙真碍事
Ugh, these guys are the pits.
为什么总是这么难?
Why is this always difficult?
你要去哪儿? 彼得
Where are you going, Peter?
有什么遗言吗?
Any last words?
能给我一分钟思考一下吗? 你带笔了吗?
Can I get a minute to think about it? Do you have a pen?
再见了  彼得·帕克
Goodbye Peter Parker.
谁在那儿?
Who did that?
迈尔斯?
Miles?
蜘蛛侠?
Spider-Man?
迈尔斯  你学会控制自己了
Wow Miles! You're doing it on command!
也是时候了  对吧?
About time right?
迈尔斯
Miles!
看看谁来了  -你做到了
Hey, look who's here!  - You figured it out.
我爱你  真为你感到骄傲
I love you! I am so proud of you!
我想要孩子吗?
Do I want kids?
好吧  忘了还有她
Oh yeah. I forgot about her.
情况看起来可不妙
Well that doesn't look promising.
对  确实不妙
No, it doesn't.
找到基因匹配了  等等
I've got genetic matches. Hold on.
风险太大了
It's too risky.
闭上嘴  快打开
Shut up and turn it up!
在你左边  -在你右边
- On your left! - On your right!
五点钟方向  三点钟  两点钟
I got five o'clock! Three o'clock! Two o'clock!
所有方向
Every direction!
快去避难所  我马上过去
Get to a shelter! I'll be right there!
快走吧  我打给学校  可怎么都打不通
Vamo senor. I've tried the school, but I can't get through!
伙计们  你们看到了吗?
Guys are you seeing this?!
看起来像是我们的宇宙正在涌向我们
Looks like our dimensions are coming to us.
看起来挺酷  不是吗?
It does look cool though, right?
我们得回到上面去
We gotta get back up there.
你就这么点本事吗?
Is that all you got?
看来你只会嘴上功夫
You gonna fight or you just bumping gums?
你这个欠揍的臭乌龟
You hard-boiled turtle slapper!
一头猪? 什么玩意儿  愚蠢的卡通人物吗?
Puerco? What are you, some kind of silly cartoon?
你对卡通人物有意见吗?
You got a problem with cartoons?
现在觉得卡通人物怎么样?
Did that feel like a cartoon?
格温
Gwen!!
战服不错
I like your suit.
谢谢  我自己做的
Thanks. I made it myself.
真可爱  伙计们  现在抓紧了
That was adorable team! Now hold on tight!
准备好  伙计们  这将会是场持久战
Buckle up guys, this is going to take a while.
好吧  当我没说
All right. Never mind.
去做个了结吧
Let's end this thing.
伙计们  交给我吧
Guys, I got it.
让我去  小玩意儿还在我的
I'll go. I'm the one with the goo...
居然上那小子的套了
Oh you gotta be kidding me.
别光顾着听  要仔细看
Don't watch the mouth. Watch the hands.
迈尔斯  小心点
Miles! Be careful!
还挺刺激的
That was crazy.
这都是我们教他的对吧?
Ah we taught him that right?
我可没教过他  更不可能是你教的
I didn't teach him that. And you definitely didn't.
你没事吧?
You okay?
走吧
C'mon...
伙计们  我控制住光波了  快上来
Guys! I got control of the beam! Get up here!
警报  量子极性正在逆转
Alert! Quantum polarity has been reversed.
看来是时候了
Guess this is it.
好吧  能找到同伴真好  对吧?
Well, nice to know we're not alone. Right?
没错
Yeah.
我打开了入口  你现走  潘妮
I got the portal open. You first Peni.
谢谢你  迈尔斯  我们俩都是
Thank you, Miles. From both of us.
我  我爱你们大家
I, uh, love you all.
我会把这小方块带回去
I'm taking this cube thing with me.
虽然我还不太会玩
I don't understand it.
但我会搞懂的
But I will.
这个送给你
I want you to have this.
可以放在口袋里
It'll fit in your pocket.
朋友们  就到这儿吧
That's all folks.
他可以这么说吗? 不侵权吗?
Is he allowed to say that? Legally?
现在能说我喜欢你的发型了吗?
Do I get to like the hairdo now?
你知道我比你大吧
You know I'm older than you.
虽然只有15个月  但我还挺介意这点的
15 months, but it's pretty significant if you ask me.
好吧  爱因斯坦说过时间是相对的  不是吗?
Well, Einstein said time was relative, right?
聪明
Nice.
朋友?
Friends?
朋友
Friends.
真棒
Cool.
回头见  蜘蛛侠
See you around Spider-Man.
该你了
Your turn.
对  是的
Yeah yeah right...
你哪都别想去
You're not going anywhere!
我去拖住他  你把机器关掉
I'll hold him off, you shut this down!
彼得  计划不是这样的
Peter, that wasn't the deal!
按绿色的按钮  千万不要等我
Push the green button! Do not wait for me!
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
彼得  你必须回家
Peter, you gotta go home!
这家伙会杀了你的
This guy could kill you! I can't let Spider-Man die.
我也不能
Neither can I.
不会有事的
It's OK.
对  不会有事的
Yeah, it is ok.
你得回家  伙计
You gotta go home man.
我怎么知道这次会不会再被我搞砸了?
How do I know I'm not gonna mess it up again?
你不会知道
You won't.
对
Right.
这是种信念
It's a leap of faith.
真不赖  小子
Not bad, kid.
金并
Kingpin!
不
Nope!
抱歉  那是作弊
Sorry! That's cheating.
再见了
Adios!
我得到按钮那儿去
I gotta get to that button.
不
Oh no...
孤军奋战没想象中那么容易吧?
Not so easy doing it on your own is it?
我迫不及待地想再杀一个蜘蛛侠
I can't wait to kill one more Spider-Man.
你在干什么? 我在哪里?
What are you doing? Where am I?
什么
What...
威尔逊
Wilson...
这就是你想要的吗?
Is this what you want man?
你在做什么? 离我们远点
What are you doing? You stay away from us.
瓦内莎? 瓦内莎  理查德
Vanessa? Vanessa! Richard!
我们怎么会在这儿?
What're we doing here?
我不知道  理查德
I don't know Richard...
瓦内莎  是我  你知道我的
Vanessa it's me. You know me!
快离开这儿
...we're leaving now.
别走
Don't go!
留下来
Stay with me.
求你了
Please!
我不会让你阻止我的  这次绝对不行
You're not stopping this. Not today.
我就要阻止你  就现在
I am stopping this! Right now!
我需要支援
I need back up!
拜托
Come on.
真正的蜘蛛侠都战胜不了我  你算什么
The real Spider-Man couldn't even beat me. You're nothing!
你夺走了我的家人
You took my family.
现在我要让你也见不到你的家人
And now I'm gonna make sure you never see yours again.
站起来  蜘蛛侠
Get up, Spider-Man!
站起来  快点
Get up! C'mon... C'mon.
拜托  拜托  拜托
C'mon... c'mon... come on...
我不会离开我的家人
I'll always have my family.
听过搭肩膀这招吗?
You ever hear of the shoulder touch?
什么?
What?
嘿
“Hey.”
嘿  金并  帮我按下绿色按钮
Hey Kingpin! Push the green button for me!
迈尔斯?  迈尔斯?  迈尔斯  你没事吧?
Miles? Miles? Miles?! Are you ok?
放心 我没事
Yeah, I'm ok.
你现在应该很忙  所以
You're probably busy so...
不  不  不  我有空  我有空
No no no no, I can talk! I can talk.
我之前去找你是因为
Look, so I came by earlier because...
你叔叔  -我知道  爸爸
- Your uncle... - I know, Dad.
我很难过
I am so sorry.
我懂
Yeah.
知道是谁干的吗?
Do you know who did it?
我以为知道  可我错了
I thought I did. But I was wrong.
听着  迈尔斯  我在门口说的那些
Look, Miles, what I said at the door,
不只是说说而已
it wasn't just talk.
听着  知道吗  我在想我们可以
Look, you know, I was thinking
找一堵不错的墙
maybe we could find a nice wall,
私人所有的
privately owned,
好的  爸爸
Ok, dad.
比如警察局那堵墙
like at the police station
这样你就可以把你的作品“丢到”墙上去了
and you could "throw up" some of your art.
我实在不擅长说这些
Man, I'm bad at this.
好吧  迈尔斯  迈尔斯?  你还在吗?
Okay, Miles. Miles? You there?
真是的  什么破信号
C'mon man, C-Mobile
警官?
Officer?
蜘蛛侠  我想说  刚才真是  我是说我欠你一个
Spider-Man. Listen, down there, that was, I mean I owe you
好吧
Okay!
很期待和你并肩作战
I look forward to working with you.
对  我想也是
Yeah, me too, I guess.
虽然我不赞同你的方式
I don't approve of your methods,
不过想法不错也许也能擦出火花
but we're just gonna have to agree to disagree.
感谢你今晚的英勇行为
Thank you for your bravery tonight.
我爱你
I love you.
等等  什么?
Wait, what?
看看你身后
And look behind you!
你友好的邻居蜘蛛侠献上
没错  是很酷  对
Alright. Cool, yeah!
谢谢你  蜘蛛侠
Yeah, thanks Spider-Man!
我是蜘蛛侠  谢谢
Yeah I'm Spider-man! A su servicio! Thank you.
你就是蜘蛛侠啊
Yeah, you the Spider-Man!
嘿  小家伙怎么了?
Hey, man. What's up, little man?
新蜘蛛侠
New Spider-Man.
对  没错  我是新蜘蛛侠
Yeah. Yeah, I'm the new Spider-Man.
看好了
Check it out.
刚才那是设计好的
Whoa! That was part of the move.
好了  我们最后再来一次
Okay, let's do this one last time, yeah?
这次是真的最后一次
For real this time. This is it.
我叫做迈尔斯·莫拉莱斯
My name is Miles Morales.
我被一只受过辐射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
于是就在最近
And for like two days,
我成了这里唯一的蜘蛛侠
I've been the one and only Spider-Man.
剩下的你们都知道了
I think you know the rest.
我写完了论文
I finished my essay.
远大前程
我写完了论文
I finished my essay.
救了不少人
Saved a bunch of people.
撞到过无人机
Got hit by a drone.
我和我爸完成了这个
I did this with my dad.
艾伦叔叔
力量永存
最后来见见我的室友
Met my roommate finally.
好兄弟
在我爸爸永远找不到的地方贴贴纸
Slapped a sticker where my Dad's never going to find it.
当我感到孤单
And when I feel alone,
感觉没人能理解自己时
like no one understands what I'm going through,
我知道我的朋友们会懂我
I remember my friends who get it.
我从没想过自己能够做到这些
I never thought I'd be able to do any of this stuff.
可我做到了
But I can.
任何人都能戴上这个面具
Anyone can wear the mask.
你也可以
You could wear the mask.
如果以前你没想过  希望现在可以
If you didn't know that before, I hope you do now.
因为我是蜘蛛侠
'Cause I'm Spider-Man.
但我不是唯一的
And I'm not the only one.
绝对不是
Not by a long shot.
♪ Needless to say
I keep her in check ♪
♪ She was all bad-bad
Nevertheless ♪
♪ Callin' it quits now
Baby, I'm a wreck... ♪
迈尔斯  迈尔斯
Miles. Miles!
你有空吗?
You got a minute?
♪ Stepped out of my zone ♪
♪ I had to get out all alone ♪
♪ And figure it out on my own ♪
♪ And I know what
I really want now ♪
♪ Can't stop me
Can't break me ♪
♪ What don't kill me
Gon' make me ♪
♪ Shoot for the stars
No safety ♪
♪ And now I see clear in HD ♪
- ♪ Gotta go hard ♪
- ♪ I ain't got time to waste ♪
- ♪ I ain't got time ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪
- ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
- ♪ They wanna fight ♪
- ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪
- ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ You gotta choose a side
You gotta choose a side ♪
♪ You better keep
You better do what's right ♪
♪ Or you gonna lose the fight ♪
- ♪ You gonna ♪
- ♪ Gotta go hard ♪
♪ Gotta choose a side ♪
♪ I'm gonna elevate ♪
- ♪ You better ♪
- ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ You better do what's right ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ Heroes never die ♪
♪ I'm a web slinger
To a gunslinger ♪
♪ No millimeter
This is my arena ♪
♪ I'm the black widow
With the best stinger ♪
♪ And I'll make you scream
Like a bad singer ♪
♪ I'm everything that you
Wanna be plus more ♪
♪ Since there's
No heroes anymore ♪
♪ Jump out the window
Him with the mask on ♪
♪ Who the bad man
That our man gotta bash on? ♪
♪ Oh, we'll never link up
Blink and you will see us ♪
♪ Young prince 'bout to ink up
See me in the NYC ♪
♪ You can never swing by me ♪
♪ Oh, we'll never link up
Blink and you will see us ♪
♪ Young prince 'bout to ink up
See me in the NYC ♪
♪ Home of the B.I.G., yo ♪
♪ They just slander me
I just plan to be ♪
♪ Something powerful
For my family ♪
♪ Tried to balance life
And my sanity ♪
♪ Show a different side
Of humanity ♪
♪ So amazing, keep upraising ♪
♪ Save you from
A home invasion ♪
♪ Chasing robbers
From the bank ♪
♪ You facing friendly
Neighborhood Spider-Man ♪
♪ Gotta go hard ♪
- ♪ I ain't got time to waste ♪
- ♪ I ain't got time ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪
- ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
- ♪ They wanna fight ♪
- ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪
- ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ Okay, I fight crime
Through the nighttime ♪
♪ When the lights shine
I go python ♪
♪ I'm falling on
My last lifeline ♪
♪ There's no way
In my right mind ♪
♪ My city up on my back tight ♪
♪ How can I possibly
Act right? ♪
♪ I'm Robin Hood
I'm the black knight ♪
♪ I know you heard
'Bout my last fight ♪
♪ 'Cause I win
Over and over again ♪
♪ Battling evil
I'm hoping to win ♪
♪ Fighting my demons
I'm nice for a reason ♪
♪ Enticed with the bleeding
I'm showing my sins ♪
♪ How can you expect me
To stay sane? ♪
♪ Protect me
My technique go X speed ♪
♪ On highways and Jet Skis ♪
♪ Look, I ain't got no time
To be hanging around nobody ♪
♪ Trying to figure out
If they good or evil ♪
♪ I'm fighting the crime
Saving your lives ♪
♪ One at a time
I'm killing the rhymes ♪
♪ I do it for the people ♪
♪ I'm Peter Parker
Running through The Six ♪
♪ With a bag full of tricks
You better choose a side ♪
♪ I can promise you
I will not lose this time ♪
♪ I did it all independent
Now we winning ♪
♪ I got my homeys
Cooking in the kitchen ♪
♪ We gon' have to win
And give us the business ♪
♪ The world is mine and you
Gon' have to pay me attention ♪
♪ I did everything
That I did on my own ♪
♪ I'm the only one for real
There can never be a clone ♪
♪ Better talk to me nice
Better watch your tone ♪
♪ And I'm putting on
For my home slice ♪
♪ So I gotta go hard ♪
♪ I gotta elevate ♪
《蜘蛛侠：平行宇宙》
当某个人去帮助别人只是源于初衷，并仅仅认为那是他(她)
应该去做的事时，那么毫无疑问这就是
真正的超级英雄。
——斯坦·李
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ I went from boy to a man,
Why? ♪
♪ Officer sure had to
Stand down ♪
♪ But I had to make
A perfect plan ♪
- ♪ I'm on a wave ♪
- ♪ Brave, brave ♪
♪ I had to fight
For the city ♪
♪ For the city ♪
- ♪ I had to fight for people ♪
- ♪ For the people ♪
♪ You gotta do
What all leaders do, go ♪
♪ Everyone here
We been needing you ♪
♪ I know you can be a hero
'Cause I seen you do it ♪
♪ This is the time
We needed you ♪
♪ Everyone is here
To see you move ♪
♪ We want it, we want it
We want it, we want it ♪
- ♪ We put our wallet away ♪
- ♪ Wallet ♪
♪ And every time
Each one of you ♪
♪ Through the city
You were saving the day, go ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ We gotta fight
For the town, town ♪
♪ Now there's no feelings
allowed, allowed ♪
♪ Everyone cheer in the crowd ♪
♪ Bought 'em so well
I'm over the clouds ♪
- ♪ We gotta fight for the city ♪
- ♪ City ♪
- ♪ Competition was lethal ♪
- ♪ Lethal ♪
- ♪ Honestly, it's no biggie ♪
- ♪ Biggie ♪
♪ I had to do
What all leaders do ♪
♪ Uh-oh
They don't want it, man ♪
They don't wanna know ♪
♪ Promise, uh-oh
They don't want it, man ♪
♪ Uh-oh
They don't wanna know ♪
♪ Promise, uh-oh
They don't want it, man ♪
♪ Uh-oh, they can't
Handle my powers ♪
♪ They always hate on us ♪
♪ But they can't do it
Without us ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We gotta clean up
These city streets ♪
- ♪ We don't accept defeat ♪
- ♪ 'Feat ♪
♪ We keep on going
Until we win ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ All of 'em weak
In the knees ♪
♪ Scary how lights
When they freeze ♪
♪ Well, we keep on going
Until we win ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Well ♪
♪ This morning
I woke up ♪
♪ In a fortress of distortion ♪
♪ I'm at war with my emotions ♪
♪ I'm at war with
They enforce me ♪
♪ Trying to fight for what's
Right, and got sidetracked ♪
♪ Where your mind at?
Never mind that ♪
♪ Got me thinking a blink
You swim and you sinking ♪
♪ You wouldn't, you leave me
Here for my loaded weapon ♪
♪ I still owe my brother
My present protection ♪
♪ My prayer, my sights
So I'm doing what's right ♪
♪ And I ask you no questions ♪
♪ I wanna be home-free ♪
♪ Where's one that was lonely ♪
♪ But I'm ready and waiting ♪
♪ For my day of salvation
And I'm patient ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm coming home, now ♪
♪ I'm coming home ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ My rebel lone yell ♪
♪ My rebel lone ♪
♪ They looking for saviors
I'm looking for safety ♪
♪ They never gonna break me
Take me ♪
♪ Down on my knees, believe ♪
♪ I'm never gonna beg
Or plead ♪
♪ I never say never
But I guarantee ♪
♪ Gather my strength
Goin' hard in the paint ♪
♪ Paint some more pictures
Put on display ♪
♪ I'm a get they don't
Get them my check ♪
♪ Can't take me down now ♪
♪ My feet on the ground now ♪
♪ Punchin' 'em on down now ♪
♪ Say it out loud now ♪
♪ Say it out loud
Are you ready for war? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm coming home now ♪
♪ I'm coming home ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ My rebel lone yell ♪
♪ My rebel lone ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh,
Spidey-bells Spidey-bells ♪
♪ Swinging through Midtown ♪
♪ Oh, what fun to sling a web ♪
♪ And take the bad guys down ♪
♪ Spidey-bells, Spidey-bells ♪
♪ Quipping all the time ♪
♪ Oh, what fun
To swing around ♪
♪ New York
While fighting crime ♪
♪ Swinging through
The streets ♪
♪ On a web of spider silk ♪
♪ Kicking all the butts ♪
♪ Of villains and their ilk ♪
♪ Bombs from Goblins fling
Fling ♪
♪ Pumpkins blooming bright
Bright ♪
♪ How hard it is
To consistently bring ♪
♪ Peace to New York all night ♪
♪ Oh, Spidey-bells
Might be swell ♪
♪ To do more than fight crime ♪
♪ I got a lot of qualities
That don't get much airtime ♪
♪ I can sing, I can dance
I tell jokes, I act ♪
♪ I get big, big, big deal ♪
♪ If my agent called me back ♪
♪ Why did I agree ♪
♪ To do this stupid song? ♪
♪ I have a degree ♪
♪ In chemical engineering ♪
与此同时  在纽约
你迟到了
You're a bit late.
我们不可能无处不在
We can't all be everywhere at once.
发个短信就好了
Little text might've been nice.
我才离开了不到两小时  发生了什么？
I was gone for less than two hours. What happened?
好的  我知道是什么了
Okay. I know what it looks like.
这可是好消息  -我们走吧
- But here's the good news. - Oh, here we go.
平行宇宙没有崩溃
The multiverse didn't collapse.
太棒了
Oh cool!
一触即溃
A little touch and go,
可是成功了
But it worked out.
很棒的故事  你弄好那个小玩意儿了吗？
Great story. Hey, did you finish the goober?
这不是个小玩意儿  是个小发明
It's not a goober. It's a gizmo.
你要叫我出去吗？
Do you always have to call me out?
这真令人沮丧  烦的一比
It's just really frustrating and bums me out.
别太激动  米盖尔
Don't get excited, Miguel.
这只是个样品  -并不激动
- It's just a prototype. - Not excited.
你可能是第一个
But you could be the first person
进入自主平行宇宙跳跃的人
to make an autonomous multiverse jump.
或许是最后一个
Or the last.
那么我们就在这孤注一掷了吗？
So we're just gonna roll the dice on this?
你觉得怎么样？ 伙计  想先去哪里？
So, what you do you say, pal? Where you want to go first?
让我们从头开始  最后一次
Let's start at the beginning one last time.
67号地球
Earth '67.
什么？
Whoa... what the...
我是蜘蛛侠  你要跟我走
I’m Spider-man. I need you to come with me.
你到底是谁？
Who the heck are you?
我刚刚告诉过你  听着  我来自未来
I just told you that, listen, listen. I'm from the future.
你竟敢指着我
How dare you point at me!
是你先指着我的
You were pointing first!
对别人指指点点很不礼貌  你太不礼貌了
- It's rude to point. - You're being very rude.
哪个先指的？
Which one pointed first?
很明显是蜘蛛侠先指的
Spider-man pointed first! Obviously!
你这么说就是在指我  我没有在指谁
- You're pointing at me right now. - I'm not pointing.
看看你的手指
Look at your finger.
我指的和你指的是不同的
I'm pointing out your pointing, which is different.
你没见到在指谁
You haven't seen pointing.
你在指着我
You're accusing me of pointing while you're...!
剧终
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-